I can’t let you out, Hedwig.
Aku tak bisa mengeluarkanmu, Hedwig.
I'm not allowed to use magic outside of school.
Aku tak boleh menggunakan sihir di luar sekolah.
-Besides, if Uncle Vernon-- -Harry Potter!
Lagipula, jika Paman Vernon...! Harry Potter!
Now you've done it.
Lihat akibat perbuatanmu.
He’s in there. Vernon?
la di sana. Vernon.
I'm warning you, if you can’t control that bloody bird, it'll have to go.
Awas, jika burung sial itu tak kaukendalikan, ia harus dibuang.
But she’s bored.
Tapi ia bosan.
If I could only let her out for an hour or two.
Kalau aku bisa mengeluarkannya satu atau dua jam saja.
So you can send secret messages to your freaky little friends? No, sir.
Agar kau bisa mengirim berita rahasia ke teman-temanmu? Tidak.
But I haven’t had any messages from any of my friends.
Tapi aku tak menerima surat dari teman-temanku.
Not one...
Tak satupun...
..-all summer.
...selama liburan musim panas ini.
Who would want to be friends with you?
Siapa yang mau berteman denganmu?
I should think you'd be a little more grateful.
Seharusnya kau lebih tahu terima kasih.
We've raised you since you were a baby, given you the food off our table...
Kami membesarkanmu sejak bayi, memberimu makan...
...even let you have Dudley’s second bedroom...
...bahkan kau boleh memakai kamar kedua Dudley,...
...purely out of the goodness of our hearts.
...semua karena kebaikan hati kami.
-Not now. It’s for when the Masons arrive. -Which should be any minute.
Jangan. Ini untuk keluarga Mason! Dan mereka sebentar lagi datang.
Now, let’s go over our schedule once again, shall we?
Sekarang, kita latih lagi jadwal kita, ya?
Petunia, when the Masons arrive, you will be...?
Petunia, jika pasangan Mason datang, kau akan?
In the lounge, waiting to welcome them graciously to our home.
Di ruang tamu, menunggu untuk mempersilakan mereka masuk.
-Good. And, Dudley, you will be...? -l'll be waiting to open the door.
Bagus. Dan kau, Dudley?! Menunggu untuk membuka pintu.
Excellent.
Sempurna.
And you?
Dan kau?
'll be in my bedroom, making no noise and pretending that I don’t exist.
Aku di kamar, berdiam diri dan berpura-pura aku tak ada.
Too right, you will.
Benar sekali.
With any luck, this could be the day I make the biggest deal of my career...
Semoga saja ini bisa menjadi bisnis terbesarku.
..-and you will not mess it up.
Dan kau tak boleh menghancurkannya.
Harry Potter, such an honor it is.
Harry Potter. Suatu kehormatan besar.
-Who are you? -Dobby, sir. Dobby the house-elf.
Siapa kau?! Dobby, Tuan. Dobby si peri rumah.
Not to be rude or anything...
Aku tak bermaksud tak sopan...
...but this isn’t a great time for me to have a house-elf in my bedroom.
...tapi sekarang bukan waktunya menerima peri rumah di kamarku.
Yes, sir. Dobby understands.
Benar, Tuan. Dobby mengerti.
It’s just that Dobby has come to tell you....
Tapi Dobby ingin mengingatkan...
It is difficult, sir. Dobby wonders where to begin.
Ini sulit, Tuan. Dobby tak tahu harus memulai dari mana.
-Why don't you sit down? -Sit down? Sit down?
Silakan duduk! Silakan duduk? Duduk?
Dobby, I’m sorry. I didn’t mean to offend you or anything.
Maaf, Dobby. Aku tak bermaksud - menyinggungmu.
Offend Dobby?
Menyinggung Dobby?
Dobby has heard of your greatness, sir...
Dobby sudah dengar kehebatan Tuan, tapi ia tak pernah...
...but never has he been asked to sit down by a wizard, like an equal.
..dipersilakan duduk oleh penyihir dan dianggap sederajat.
You can’t have met many decent wizards then.
Kalau begitu tak banyak penyihir baik yang kautemui.
No, I haven't.
Benar.
That was an awful thing to say.
Aku tak boleh mengatakannya.
-Bad Dobby! Bad Dobby! -Stop, Dobby. Dobby, shush.
Dobby nakal! Dobby nakal!! Hentikan, Dobby.
Dobby, please, stop.
Kumohon, berhentilah, Dobby.
Don't mind that. It’s just the cat.
Jangan perhatikan. Itu hanya suara kucing.
-Bad Dobby. -Stop! Stop, Dobby. Please, be quiet.
Dobby nakal! Berhenti, Dobby! Jangan berisik.
Are you all right?
Kau baik-baik saja?
Dobby had to punish himself, sir.
Dobby harus menghukum diri.
Dobby almost spoke ill of his family, sir.
Dobby hampir saja menjelek-jelekkan keluarganya.
-Your family? -The wizard family Dobby serves, sir.
Keluargamu?! Keluarga penyihir majikan Dobby.
Dobby is bound to serve one family forever.
Dobby ditakdirkan untuk selamanya melayani satu keluarga.
If they ever knew Dobby was here....
Kalau mereka tahu Dobby ke sini...
But Dobby had to come. Dobby has to protect Harry Potter. To warn him.
Tapi Dobby harus datang dan melindungi Harry. Memperingatkan.
Harry Potter must not go back...
Harry Potter tak boleh kembali...
...to Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry this year.
..ke Sekolah Sihir Hogwarts tahun ini.
There is a plot, a plot to make most terrible things happen.
Ada seseorang yang merencanakan hal yang sangat mengerikan.
What terrible things? Who's plotting them?
Hal mengerikan apa? Siapa yang merencanakan?
Can't say.
Tak bisa bilang.
-Okay, l understand. You can't say. -Don't make me talk. I--
Baik. Aku paham. Kau tak bisa' Jangan paksa aku bicara. Aku...
-Dobby. Dobby, put the lamp down. -Bad Dobby.
Dobby, letakkan lampunya! Dobby nakal.
So when they arrive at the ninth hole....
Jadi begitu mereka tiba di lubang ke sembilan...
Give me the lamp.
Berikan lampu itu.
Dobby, stop!
Dobby, hentikan!
-Let me go. -Get in there and keep quiet.
Lepaskan aku! Masuk ke sana dan jangan ribut.
-What the devil are you doing up here? -l was just--
Apa yang kaulakukan di sini?! Aku hanya...
You just ruined the punch line of my Japanese golfer joke.
Kau baru saja merusak leluconku tentang pemain golf Jepang.
Sorry.
Maaf.
One more sound and you'll wish you'd never been born, boy.
Satu lagi suara, kau akan menyesal dilahirkan.
-And fix that door. -Yes, sir.
Dan perbaiki pintu lemarinya! Baik, Pak.
See why I've got to go back?
Kau lihat kenapa aku harus kembali?
I don’t belong here. I belong in your world, at Hogwarts.
Di sini bukan tempatku. Tempatku di duniamu. Di Hogwarts.
-It’s the only place I’ve got friends. -Friends who don't write to Harry Potter?
Hanya di sana aku punya teman!Teman yang tak pernah mengirim surat?
Well, 1 expect they've been....
Sebenarnya aku mengharapkan mereka...
Hang on. How do you know my friends haven't been writing to me?
Tunggu. Dari mana kau tahu teman-temanku tak mengirimiku surat?
Harry Potter mustn't be angry with Dobby.
Harry Potter jangan marah pada Dobby.
Dobby hoped if Harry Potter thought his friends had forgotten him...
Dobby pikir jika Harry Potter anggap teman-temannya melupakan dia,...
...Harry Potter might not want to go back to school, sir.
...Harry Potter mungkin tak mau kembali ke sekolah.
-Give me those. Now. -No!
Berikan surat-suratnya. Sekarang! Tidak!
Dobby, get back here.
Dobby, kembali ke sini.
Dobby, please, no.
Dobby. Kumohon, jangan.
Harry Potter must say he’s not going back to school.
Harry Potter harus berjanji tak akan kembali ke sekolah.
I can’t. Hogwarts is my home.
Aku tak bisa. Hogwarts adalah rumahku.
Then Dobby must do it, sir, for Harry Potter’s own good.
Maka Dobby terpaksa melakukannya. Demi kebaikan Harry Potter.
It spread as far as the eye could see, all over the floor of this building.
Lalu menyebar di mana-mana, di seluruh lantai bangunan.
One plumber said, “Look at all that water.”
Satu tukang pipa mengatakan, “Lihat air sebanyak itu."
The second plumber said, "Yes, and that’s just the top of it.”
Tukang pipa kedua mengatakan, “Ya, dan itu baru bagian atasnya."
I'm so sorry. It's my nephew. He’s very disturbed.
Maaf. Ini keponakanku. Pikirannya agak terganggu.
Meeting strangers upsets him. That's why I kept him upstairs.
Orang asing membuatnya marah. Karena itulah kami mengurungnya.
You're never going back to that school.
Kau takkan pernah kembali ke sekolah itu.
You're never going to see those freaky friends of yours again. Never!
Kau tak akan bertemu teman-temanmu lagi. Takkan pernah!
Hiya, Harry.
Hai, Harry!
Ron. Fred. George. What are you all doing here?
Ron. Fred. George. Apa yang kalian lakukan di sini?
Rescuing you, of course. Now, come on, get your trunk.
Menyelamatkanmu, tentu saja. Sekarang, kemasi kopermu.
You better stand back.
Sebaiknya kau mundur.
Let’s go.
Ayo.
-What was that? -What was it?
Apa itu?! Ada apa?
Potter!
Potter!
Dad, what's going on?
Ada apa, Yah?
Go. Go. Go.
Cepat. Cepat. Cepat.
Dad, hurry up.
Cepat, Ayah.
-Come on. -Come on, Harry, hurry up.
Ayol Ayo, Harry. Cepat.
Petunia, he’s escaping!
Petunia, ia kabur!
-I’ve got you, Harry. -Come here!
Aku memegangimu, Harry! Kemari kau!
-Let go of me! -No, boy!
Lepaskan aku!! Tidak!
You and that bloody pigeon aren't going anywhere.
Kau dan merpati sialmu tak boleh pergi.
-Get off! -Drive!
Lepaskan!! Jalan!
-Right. -Right!
Baik.
No! No! No! No!
Tidak!
Dad!
Ayah!
Damn.
Sial.
By the way, Harry, happy birthday.
Omong-omong, selamat ulang tahun, Harry.
Come on.
Ayo.
Okay, come on.
Baiklah, ayo.
-Think it'd be all right if we had some? -Yeah, Mum will never know.
Menurutmu tak apa-apa jika kita makan ini?!Ya. Ibu takkan tahu.
It’s not much, but it’s home.
Rumah kami tak seberapa, tapi nyaman bagi kami.
I think it’s brilliant.
Ini hebat sekali.
Where have you been?
Dari mana saja kalian?
Harry, how wonderful to see you, dear.
Senang sekali bertemu denganmu, Harry.
Beds empty. No note. Car gone.
Ranjang kalian kosong. Tak ada pesan. Mobil hilang.
You could have died. You could have been seen.
Kalian bisa celaka. Kalian bisa terlihat.
Of course, I don't blame you, Harry, dear.
Tentu saja, aku tak menyalahkanmu, Harry.
They were starving him, Mum. There were bars on his window.
Mereka membuatnya kelaparan, Bu. Memasang jeruji di jendelanya.
Well, you best hope I don’t put bars on your window, Ronald Weasley.
Berharap saja aku tak memasangnya di jendelamu, Ronald Weasley.
Come on, Harry, time for a spot of breakfast.
Ayo, Harry. Sekarang waktunya sarapan.
Here we are, Harry. Now, tuck in.
Ini, Harry. Sekarang, makanlah.
That's it. There we go.
Bagus. Pintar.
-Mummy, have you seen my jumper? -Yes, dear, it was on the cat.
Ibu lihat baju hangatku?! Ya, sayang. Ada di gantungan..
Hello.
Halo.
What did I do?
Apa salahku?
Ginny. She’s been talking about you all summer. A bit annoying, really.
Ginny. Ia membicarakanmu sepanjang liburan. Agak mengesalkan juga.
-Morning, Weasleys. -Morning, Dad.
Pagi, keluarga Weasley!! Pagi, Ayah.
-What a night. Nine raids. Nine! -Raids?
Malam yang melelahkan. Sembilan razia!!Razia?
Dad works in the Ministry of Magic, in the Misuse of Muggle Artifacts Office.
Ayah bekerja di Kementrian Sihir, di Penyalahgunaan Barang Muggle.
Dad loves Muggles, thinks they're fascinating.
Ayah suka sekali para Muggle, menurutnya mereka menyenangkan.
Well, now.
Nah.
And who are you?
Siapa kau?
Sorry, sir. I’m Harry, sir. Harry Potter.
Maaf, Pak. Aku Harry. Harry Potter.
Good Lord. Are you really?
Astaga. Sungguh?
Well, Ron has told us all about you, of course. When did he get here?
Ron sudah banyak cerita tentangmu. Kapan ia datang?
This morning.
Pagi ini.
Your sons flew that enchanted car of yours to Surrey and back last night.
Anak-anak terbangkan mobil ajaibmu semalam, pulang pergi ke Surrey.
Did you really? How did it go?
Sungguh? Bagaimana jalannya?
I mean-- That was very wrong indeed, boys. Very wrong of you.
Maksudku. Kalian lancang sekali. Lancang sekali.
Now, Harry, you must know all about Muggles.
Kau pasti tahu banyak tentang para Muggle, Harry.
Tell me, what exactly is the function of a rubber duck?
Sebenarnya apa kegunaan bebek karet?
Well, that'll be Errol with the post.
Itu pasti Errol membawa surat.
Fetch it, will you, Percy, please?
Jemput dia, Percy.
-Errol. -He’s always doing that.
Errolf la selalu begitu.
Look, it’s our Hogwarts letters. They've sent us Harry's as well.
Surat dari Hogwarts. Mereka juga mengirim untuk Harry.
Dumbledore must know you're here. Doesn't miss a trick, that man.
Dumbledore pasti tahu kau di sini. latak bisa dibohongi.
-No. -This lot won't come cheap.
Tidak Buku-buku ini tak murah.
-The spell books alone are very expensive. -We'll manage.
Buku mantra saja harganya mahal! Kita pasti bisa membelinya.
There’s only one place we're going to get all of this. Diagon Alley.
Hanya satu tempat untuk membeli. Diagon Alley.
Right.
Benar.
Here we are, Harry. You go first, dear.
Ini, Harry. Kau duluan, sayang.
But Harry’s never traveled by Floo powder before, Mum.
Tapi Harry tak pernah pergi dengan bubuk Floo, Bu.
Floo powder?
Bubuk Floo?
You go first, Ron, so that Harry can see how it’s done. Yes.
Kau pergi dulu, Ron, supaya Harry bisa melihat caranya. Ya.
In you go.
Masuklah.
That's it.
Bagus.
Diagon Alley.
Diagon Alley.
You see? It’s quite easy, dear. Don't be afraid. Come on.
Lihat? Caranya mudah, sayang. Jangan takut. Ayo.
Come on.
Ayo.
In you go. That's it. Mind your head.
Masuklah. Bagus. Awas kepalamu.
That’s right. Now, take your Floo powder.
Benar. Sekarang ambil bubuk Floo-nya.
That's it, very good.
Bagus sekali.
Now, don't forget to speak very, very clearly.
Jangan lupa bicaralah yang jelas sekali.
Diagonally.
Diagonally.
-What did he say, dear? -Diagonally.
Apa katanya, sayang?!
I thought he did.
Sudah kuduga.
-Not lost, are you, my dear? -I'm fine, thank you. I was just going....
Kau tersasar, Nak?! Tidak, terima kasih. Aku...
Come with us. We'll help you find your way back.
Ikutlah dengan kami. Kami antar kau pulang.
-No. Please-- -Harry?
Tidak. Aku mohon...! Harry?
Hagrid!
Hagrid!
What do you think you're doing down here? Come on.
Sedang apa kau di sini? Ayo.
You're a mess, Harry. Skulking around Knockturn Alley? Dodgy place.
Kau berantakan. Berkeliaran di Knockturn Alley? Ini tempat buruk.
Don't want no one to see you there. People will think you're up to no good.
Jangan sampai terlihat di sana. Kau akan dianggap penyihir buangan.
I was lost, I--
Aku tersasar. Aku...
Hang on. What were you doing down there then?
Tunggu. Kalau begitu apa yang kaulakukan di sana?
Me? I was.... 1 was looking for Flesh-Eating Slug Repellent.
Aku? Aku mencari Pembasmi Siput-Pemakan-Daging.
They're ruining all the school cabbages.
Mereka memakani kol-kol sekolah.
Harry. Hagrid.
Harry. Hagrid.
Hello, Hermione.
Halo, Hermione.
-It’s so good to see you. -It’s great to see you too.
Senang sekali bertemu lagi! Aku juga.
What did you do to your glasses?
Kacamatamu kenapa?
Oculus Reparo.
Oculus Reparo.
I definitely need to remember that one.
Aku harus mengingat mantra itu.
You'll be all right now then, Harry? Right. I'll leave you to it.
Kau sudah aman sekarang, Harry? Baiklah. Aku tinggalkan dulu.
-Okay, bye. -Thank you. Bye.
Baiklah, sampai nanti Terima kasih. Sampai nanti.
Come on, everyone's been so worried.
Ayo, semua khawatir sekali padamu.
Harry.
Harry.
Thank goodness. We'd hoped you'd only gone one grate too far.
Syukurlah. Kami berharap kau hanya tersasar sedikit.
Ladies and gentlemen, Mr. Gilderoy Lockhart.
Hadirin sekalian, Tn. Gilderoy Lockhart.
Here he is.
Itu dia.
Mum fancies him.
Ibu tergila-gila padanya.
Make way there, please. Let me by, madam. Thank you.
Tolong beri jalan, Nyonya. Terima kasih.
Excuse me, little girl. This is for the Daily Prophet.
Permisi, gadis cilik. Ini untuk Daily Prophet.
It can’t be. Harry Potter?
Tak mungkin. Harry Potter?
Harry Potter!
Harry Potter!
Excuse me, madam.
Permisi, Nyonya.
Nice big smile, Harry. Together, you and I rate the front page.
Senyum lebar, Harry. Kita berdua akan masuk halaman depan.
Ladies and gentlemen, what an extraordinary moment this is.
Hadirin sekalian, ini kesempatan yang luar biasa.
When young Harry stepped into Flourish and Blotts this morning...
Saat Harry memasuki toko buku Flourish and Bloots pagi ini...
...to purchase my autobiography, Magical Me...
..untuk membeli otobiografiku, AKU YANG AJAIB...
... Which, incidentally, is currently celebrating...
...yang secara kebetulan, sedang merayakan...
..its 27th week atop the Daily Prophet bestseller list...
..minggu ke-27-nya di puncak buku terlaris Daily Prophet.
..-he had no idea that he would, in fact, be leaving...
la tak sadar bahwa ia akan pulang...
...with my entire collected works...
...membawa seluruh koleksi karya lengkapku...
...free of charge.
..dengan gratis.
Now, ladies?
Sekarang, Nona-nona?
Harry, now you give me those, and I'll get them signed.
Harry, berikan buku-bukumu. Kumintakan tanda tangan padanya.
All of you wait outside. That's it.
Kalian semua tunggu di luar. Bagus.
I'll bet you loved that, didn’t you, Potter?
Kau pasti suka itu, bukan?
Famous Harry Potter. Can't even go into a bookshop without making the front page.
Harry Potter yang tenar. Ke toko bukupun harus jadi berita.
Leave him alone.
Jangan ganggu dia.
Look, Potter. You've got yourself a girlfriend.
Lihat, Potter. Kau punya pacar.
Now, now, Draco, play nicely.
Tenang, Draco. Jangan kasar.
Mr. Potter.
Tn. Potter.
Lucius Malfoy. We meet at last.
Lucius Malfoy. Akhirnya kita bertemu juga.
Forgive me.
Maafkan aku.
Your scar is legend.
Bekas lukamu terkenal sekali.
As, of course, is the wizard who gave it to you.
Seperti juga penyihir yang memberinya.
Voldemort killed my parents.
Voldemort membunuh orang tuaku.
He was nothing more than a murderer.
latak lebih dari seorang pembunuh.
You must be very brave to mention his name.
Berani sekali kau menyebut namanya.
Or very foolish.
Atau bodoh sekali.
Fear of a name only increases fear of the thing itself.
Takut pada sebuah nama hanya menambah rasa takut itu sendiri.
And you must be Miss Granger.
Dan kau pasti Nona Granger.
Yes, Draco has told me all about you. And your parents.
Draco sudah menceritakan padaku semua tentangmu. Dan orang tuamu.
Muggles, aren't they?
Mereka Muggle, bukan?
Let me see. Red hair, vacant expressions...
Coba kulihat. Rambut merah, ekspresi tolol.
...tatty, secondhand book.
Lusuh dan buku bekas.
You must be the Weasleys.
Kalian pasti keluarga Weasley.
It’s mad in here. Let’s go outside.
Anak-anak, di sini terlalu ramai. Ayo kita keluar.
-Well, well, well. Weasley senior. -Lucius.
Ternyata Weasley Senior! Lucius.
Busy time at the Ministry, Arthur, all those extra raids?
Sibuk di Kementrian, Arthur? Dengan razia-razia itu?
I do hope they’re paying you overtime...
Kuharap mereka membayar uang lemburmu.
...but judging by the state of this, I'd say not.
Tapi melihat keadaanmu, kurasa tidak.
What's the use in being a disgrace to the name of wizard...
Apa gunanya mempermalukan kalangan sihir...
...if they don’t even pay you well for it?
..jika mereka tak menggajimu banyak untuk melakukannya?
We have a very different idea about what disgraces the name of wizard, Malfoy.
Pengertian kita lain tentang mempermalukan dunia sihir, Malfoy.
Clearly.
Sudah jelas.
Associating with Muggles.
Bergaul dengan para Muggle.
And I thought your family could sink no lower.
Dan kupikir keluargamu sudah cukup terpuruk.
I'll see you at work.
Sampai ketemu di kantor.
See you at school.
Sampai ketemu di sekolah.
-10:58. Come on. -The train will be leaving any moment.
Kereta 58, ayo! Keretanya akan segera berangkat.
Fred, George, Percy, you first.
Fred, George, Percy, kalian duluan.
Okay.
Baik.
After you, dear.
Kau dulu, sayang.
Come on, Ginny, we'll get you a seat. Hurry.
Ayo, Ginny, kami akan carikan kursi untukmu. Cepat.
Let’s go.
Ayo.
-What do you two think you're doing? -Sorry.
Apa yang kalian lakukan?! Maaf.
Lost control of the trolley.
Troli ini lepas kendali.
-Why can’t we get through? -I don’t know.
Kenapa kita tak bisa menembusnya?! Aku tak tahu.
The gateway has sealed itself for some reason.
Pasti ada alasan kenapa gerbangnya menutup sendiri.
The train leaves at exactly 11:00. We've missed it.
Kereta berangkat tepat jam 11:00. Kita pasti ketinggalan.
Harry, if we can’t get through...
Harry, kalau kita tak bisa menembusnya...
... maybe Mum and Dad can't get back.
..mungkin ayah dan ibu tak bisa kembali.
Maybe we should just go and wait by the car.
Mungkin kita tunggu saja mereka di mobil.
The car.
Mobil?
Ron, I should tell you...
Ron, kuingatkan padamu...
...most Muggles aren't accustomed to seeing a flying car.
..kebanyakan kaum Muggle tak biasa melihat mobil terbang.
Right.
Benar.
Okay.
Baiklah.
Oh, no! The Invisibility Booster must be faulty.
Oh, tidak! Alat Pembuat Tak Tampak-nya pasti rusak.
Come on, then. Let’s go lower. We need to find the train.
Ayo, kita terbang merendah. Kita harus mencari keretanya.
Okay.
Baiklah.
All we need to do is catch up with the train.
Kita harus mengejar keretanya.
We can't be far behind.
Pasti kita belum jauh tertinggal.
-Do you hear that? -We must be getting close.
Kau dengar itu?! Pasti kita sudah dekat.
Hold on.
Tunggu dulu.
Harry!
Harry!
Hold on!
Bertahanlah!
Take my hand!
Tangkap tanganku!
I'm trying. Your hand's all sweaty.
Sudah kucoba. Tanganmu berkeringat.
-l think we found the train. -Yeah.
Kurasa kita sedah temukan keretanya! Ya.
Welcome home.
Selamat datang.
Up! Up!
Naik! Naik!
It’s not working!
Tak bisa!
Up! Ron, mind that tree!
Naik! Ron, awas pohon itu!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Berhenti!
-My wand. Look at my wand. -Be thankful it’s not your neck.
Tongkat sihirku. Lihat Bersyukurlah itu bukan lehermu.
-What’s happening? -I don’t know.
Apa yang terjadi?! Entahlah.
Come on, go! Fast!
Ayo kita pergi! Cepat!
Scabbers, you're okay.
Scabbers, kau baik-baik saja.
The car!
Mobilnya!
Dad's gonna kill me.
Ayah pasti membunuhku.
See you, Hedwig.
Sampai nanti, Hedwig.
So a house-elf shows up in my bedroom...
Jadi peri rumah muncul di kamarku.
...we can't get through the barrier to platform 9 34...
Kita tak bisa menembus gerbang penghalang di peron 9 34.
...we almost get killed by a tree....
Kita hampir tewas dibunuh sebatang pohon.
Clearly someone doesn’t want me here this year.
Pasti ada yang tak ingin aku kembali ke sini tahun ini.
Well, take a good look, lads.
Lihat baik-baik, anak-anak.
This night might well be the last you spend in this castle.
Malam ini mungkin akan jadi malam terakhir kalian di kastil.
Oh, dear, we are in trouble.
Astaga, celaka kita.
You were seen by no less than seven Muggles.
Kau terlihat oleh tak kurang dari tujuh Muggle.
Do you have any idea how serious this is?
Kalian sadar betapa seriusnya ini?
You have risked the exposure of our world.
Kau bisa menyebabkan terungkapnya dunia kita
Not to mention the damage you inflicted on a Whomping Willow...
Dan kalian juga merusak pohon Dedalu Perkasa...
...that’s been on these grounds since before you were born.
...yang sudah ada sejak sebelum kalian lahir.
Honestly, Professor Snape, I think it did more damage to us.
Profesor Snape, pohon itu lebih merusak kami...
Silence.
Diam.
l assure you that were you in Slytherin, and your fate rested with me...
Jika di Slytherin, dan nasib kalian tergantung padaku,...
...the both of you would be on the train home tonight.
..kalian berdua akan kupulangkan dengan kereta malam ini.
-As it is-- -They are not.
Karena...! Tidak.
Professor Dumbledore. Professor McGonagall.
Profesor Dumbledore. Profesor McGonagall.
Headmaster...
Kepala Sekolah, mereka melanggar...
...these boys have flouted the Decree for the Restriction of Underage Wizardry.
...Dekrit Pembatasan Masuk Akal bagi Penyihir di Bawah-Umur.
-As such-- -l am well aware of our bylaws, Severus...
Seperti...! Aku tahu peraturan kita, Severus.
. having written quite a few of them myself.
Bahkan beberapa peraturan juga aku yang menulisnya.
However, as head of Gryffindor house...
Tetapi, sebagai kepala asrama Gryffindor...
..jit is for Professor McGonagall to determine the appropriate action.
..tugas Profesor McGonagall-lah untuk menetapkan hukumannya.
We'll go and get our stuff, then.
Kalau begitu kami akan mengemasi barang-barang kami.
What are you talking about, Mr. Weasley?
Apa maksudmu, Tn. Weasley?
You're going to expel us, aren’t you?
Profesor akan mengeluarkan kami dari sekolah, bukan?
Not today, Mr. Weasley...
Tidak hari ini, Tn. Weasley.
...but I must impress on both of you the seriousness of what you have done.
Tapi aku terkesan atas kerusakan serius yang kalian akibatkan.
I will be writing to your families tonight, and you will both receive detention.
Aku akan surati keluarga kalian, dan kalian akan menerima hukuman.
Morning, everyone.
Selamat pagi, semuanya.
-Good morning, everyone. -Good morning, Professor Sprout.
Selamat pagi, semuanya! Selamat pagi, Profesor Sprout.
Welcome to Greenhouse Three, second years. Gather around, everyone.
Selamat datang di Rumah Kaca Tiga, siswa kelas dua. Ayo, berkumpul.
Today we're going to re-pot Mandrakes.
Hari ini kita akan menanam semai Mandrake di dalam pot.
Who here can tell me the properties of the Mandrake root?
Siapa yang bisa memberitahu kegunaan akar Mandrake?
Yes, Miss Granger?
Ya, Nona Granger?
Mandrake, or Mandragora...
Mandrake, atau Mandragora...
...is used to return those who have been Petrified to their original state.
...berkhasiat menawarkan kutukan orang yang tersihir.
It’s also quite dangerous. The Mandrake’s cry is fatal to anyone who hears it.
Tapi membahayakan. Tangisan Mandrake berakibat fatal jika didengar.
Excellent. Ten points to Gryffindor.
Bagus sekali. Sepuluh nilai untuk Gryffindor.
As our Mandrakes are still only seedlings...
Karena Mandrake kita masih berupa tanaman semai...
...their cries won't kill you yet.
...tangisan mereka belum bisa membunuh kalian.
But they could knock you out for several hours, which is why I have given you earmuffs...
Tapi bisa membuat pingsan, dan itulah guna penutup telinga.
...for auditory protection.
Untuk melindungi pendengaran.
So could you please put them on, tight away? Quickly.
Jadi segera kalian pakai. Cepat.
Flaps tight down, and watch me closely.
Pasang rapat-rapat penutupnya, dan perhatikan baik-baik.
You grasp your Mandrake firmly.
Genggam erat Mandrake.
You pull it sharply up out of the pot.
Tarik dengan cepat dari dalam pot.
Got it? And...
Mengerti? Dan...
..-now you dunk it down into the other pot...
..sekarang masukkan ke dalam pot lain.
...and pour a little sprinkling of soil to keep him warm.
Dan taburi sedikit tanah untuk menghangatkannya.
Longbottom’s been neglecting his earmuffs.
Longbottom pasti lupa memasang tutup telinganya.
-No, ma’am, he’s just fainted. -Yes, well, just leave him there.
Tidak, ia memang mudah pingsan! Ya. Kita biarkan saja.
Right, on we go. Plenty of pots to go around.
Kita teruskan. Masih banyak pot untuk dikerjakan.
Grasp your Mandrake and pull it up.
Genggam erat Mandrake-nya dan tarik.
-There’s Nearly Headless Nick. -Hello, Percy, Miss Clearwater.
Itu Nick si Kepala-Nyaris-Putus! Halo, Percy, Nona Clearwater.
Hello, Sir Nicholas.
Halo, Sir Nicholas.
Say it. I'm doomed.
Katakan. Celaka aku.
-You're doomed. -Hi, Harry.
Celaka kau! Hai, Harry.
I'm Colin Creevey. I'm in Gryffindor too.
Aku Colin Creevey. Aku juga masuk ke Gryffindor.
Hi, Colin. Nice to meet you.
Hai, Colin. Senang berkenalan denganmu.
Ron, is that your owl?
Ron, itu burung hantumu?
Bloody bird’s a menace.
Burung ini pengacau berat.
Oh, no.
Oh, tidak.
Look, everyone. Weasley'’s got himself a Howler.
Lihat, semuanya. Weasley dapat Howler.
Go on, Ron. I ignored one from my gran once. It was horrible.
Buka, Ron. Aku pernah abaikan Howler nenekku. Jadinya lebih mengerikan.
Ronald Weasley!
Ronald Weasley!
How dare you steal that car! ! am absolutely disgusted!
Lancang sekali kau mencuri mobil! Aku murka sekali!
Your father's now facing an inquiry at work...
Sekarang ayahmu diinterogasi di kantornya...
.and it's entirely your fault!
...dan itu semua salahmu!
if you put another toe out of line...
Kalau kau sekali lagi berbuat nakal...
...we'll bring you straight home!
..kami akan segera menjemputmu pulang!
And, Ginny, dear, congratulations on making Gryffindor.
Dan selamat, Ginny. Kau berhasil masuk ke Gryffindor.
Your father and { are so proud.
Ayah dan Ibu bangga sekali.
Let me introduce you to your new Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher.
Aku ingin memperkenalkan guru baru Pertahanan Terhadap Ilmu Hitam.
Me.
Aku.
Gilderoy Lockhart...
Gilderoy Lockhart.
..-Order of Merlin, Third Class...
Order of Merlin, Kelas Ketiga.
..-honorary member of the Dark Force Defense League...
Anggota kehormatan Liga Pertahanan Terhadap Ilmu Hitam.
...and five times winner...
Dan pemenang lima kali...
...of Witch Weekly's Most-Charming-Smile Award.
..kontes Senyum-Paling-Menawan majalah Witch Weekly.
But I don’t talk about that.
Tapi aku tak mau membicarakan itu.
I didn’t get rid of the Bandon Banshee by smiling at him.
Aku tak mengusir Bandon Banshee dengan tersenyum padanya.
Now, be warned.
Sekarang, bersiaplah.
It is my job to arm you...
Sudah tugasku untuk mempersenjatai kalian...
.. against the foulest creatures known to wizardkind.
..melawan mahluk paling mengerikan di dunia sihir.
You may find yourselves facing your worst fears in this room.
Mungkin kalian akan menghadapi ketakutan terbesar kalian.
Know only that no harm can befall you whilst 1 am here.
Tapi kalian akan aman selama aku di sini.
I must ask you not to scream.
Kuminta kalian tak menjerit.
It might provoke them.
Jeritan kalian bisa memprovokasi mereka.
Cornish pixies?
Pixie Cornish?
Freshly caught Cornish pixies.
Pixie Cornish yang baru tertangkap.
Laugh if you will, Mr. Finnegan...
Tertawalah, Tn. Finnegan.
...but pixies can be devilishly tricky little blighters.
Tapi mereka bisa jadi pemusnah yang licik sekali.
Let's see what you make of them.
Kita lihat kalian jadikan apa mereka.
Come on now, round them up. They're only pixies.
Ayo, kumpulkan mereka. Mereka hanya pixie biasa.
-You just stay there! -Please, get me down!
Diam di sini!! Tolong, turunkan aku!
-Get off me! -Stop. Hold still!
Lepaskan aku!! Berhenti. Jangan bergerak!
Peskipiksi Pesternomi!
Peskipiksi Pesternomi!
l'll ask you three to just nip the rest of them back into their cage.
Kalian bertiga kuminta mengembalikan mereka ke sangkar.
What do we do now?
Apa yang harus kita lakukan?
immobulus!
Immobulus!
Why is it always me?
Kenapa selalu aku?
I spent the summer devising a whole new Quidditch program.
Kuhabiskan liburan musim panasku merancang program baru @uidditch.
We're gonna train earlier, harder and longer.
Kita akan berlatih lebih pagi, lebih keras dan lebih lama.
What--? I don’t believe it.
Apa? Aku tak percaya ini.
-Where you think you're going, Flint? -Quidditch practice.
Kau mau ke mana, Flint?! Berlatih @uidditch.
-l booked the pitch for Gryffindor today. -Easy, Wood. I've got a note.
Lapangan sudah dipesan Gryffindor! Tenang, Wood. Aku ada surat ijin.
I smell trouble.
Aku mencium masalah.
"I, Professor Severus Snape, do hereby give the Slytherin team...
“Aku, Profesor Severus Snape, memberi ijin tim Slytherin...
...permission to practice today, owing to the need to train their new Seeker.”
..untuk berlatih hari ini, demi melatih Seeker baru mereka."
You've got a new Seeker. Who?
Kalian punya Seeker baru? Siapa?
-Malfoy? -That’s right.
Malfoy?! Benar.
And that’s not all that’s new this year.
Dan bukan hanya itu yang baru tahun ini.
Those are Nimbus 2001s. How did you get those?
Itu Nimbus 2001. Dari mana kalian dapat itu?
A gift from Draco’s father.
Hadiah dari ayah Draco.
You see, Weasley, unlike some, my father can afford the best.
Tak seperti keluarga lain, ayahku bisa membeli yang terbaik.
At least no one on the Gryffindor team had to buy their way in.
Setidaknya anggota tim Gryffindor tak perlu menyuap untuk masuk.
They got in on pure talent.
Mereka mendapatkannya murni dari bakatnya.
No one asked your opinion, you filthy little Mudblood.
Tak ada yang tanya pendapatmu, Darah-lumpur jelek.
You'll pay for that one, Malfoy. Eat slugs!
Kau harus bayar ucapanmu, Malfoy. Makanlah siput!
You okay, Ron?
Kau baik-baik saja, Ron?
Say something.
Katakan sesuatu.
-Wow! Can you turn him around, Harry? -No, Colin, get out of the way.
Kau bisa membalik mantranya?! Tidak. Minggir, Colin.
Let’s take him to Hagrid’s.
Kita bawa dia ke rumah Hagrid.
He’ll know what to do.
la tahu apa yang harus dilakukan.
This calls for a specialist's equipment.
Ini membutuhkan peralatan ahlinya.
Nothing to do but wait till it stops, I'm afraid.
Kita tak bisa berbuat apa-apa selain menunggu sampai berhenti.
-Okay. -Better out than in.
Baiklah! Lebih baik keluar, daripada masuk.
-Who was Ron trying to curse, anyway? -Malfoy. He called Hermione....
Siapa yang ingin dikutuk Ron?! Malfoy. Ia mengatai Hermione...
Well, I don’t know exactly what it means.
Aku juga tak tahu apa artinya.
He called me a Mudblood.
la mengataiku Darah-lumpur.
-He did not. -What’s a Mudblood?
Tak mungkin! Apa artinya Darah-lumpur?
It means "dirty blood." Mudblood’s a really foul name for someone who's Muggle-born.
Artinya darah kotor. Itu julukan penyihir kelahiran Muggle.
Someone with non-magic parents. Someone like me.
Yang orang tuanya tak punya keahlian sihir. Seperti aku.
It’s not a term one usually hears in civilized conversation.
Biasanya penyihir modern tak pernah menyebutnya lagi.
See, the thing is, Harry, there are some wizards, like the Malfoy family...
Masalahnya, ada beberapa penyihir, seperti keluarga Malfoy...
...who think they're better than everyone else because they're pure-blood.
...yang menganggap dirinya lebih baik hanya karena berdarah murni.
That's horrible.
Mengerikan sekali.
It’s disgusting.
Menjijikkan.
And it’s codswallop to boot. Dirty blood.
Dan tak pantas dilontarkan. Darah-lumpur.
Why, there isn’t a wizard alive today that’s not half-blood or less.
Tak ada penyihir jaman sekarang yang berdarah murni.
More to the point, they've yet to think of a spell that our Hermione can't do.
Lagipula, tak ada mantra yang tak bisa dilakukan Hermione.
Come here.
Kemarilah.
Don't you think on it, Hermione. Don't you think on it for one minute.
Jangan dipikirkan, Hermione. Jangan sekalipun kaupikirkan.
Harry, Harry, Harry.
Harry, Harry, Harry.
Can you possibly imagine...
Kau bisa bayangkan...
...a better way to serve detention...
..cara lain yang lebih baik menjalani hukumanmu...
...than by helping me to answer my fan mail?
...selain membantuku menjawab surat-surat penggemarku?
Not really.
Tidak juga.
Fame is a fickle friend, Harry. Celebrity is as celebrity does.
Ketenaran itu tidak abadi, Harry. Orang jadi tenar karena sikapnya.
Remember that.
Ingat itu.
Come.
Datanglah.
Come...
Datanglah...
...to me.
..padaku.
-What? -Sorry?
Apa?! Maaf?
That voice.
Suara itu.
Voice?
Suara?
-Didn’t you hear it? -What are you talking about, Harry?
Profesor tak dengar?! Apa maksudmu, Harry?
I think you're getting a bit drowsy.
Kurasa kau mulai mengantuk.
And great Scott, no wonder. Look at the time. We've been here nearly four hours.
Tak heran. Jam berapa sekarang? Kita di sini hampir empat jam.
Spooky how the time flies when one is having fun.
Menyeramkan juga jika waktu lewat begitu cepat di tengah kesenangan.
Spooky.
Menyeramkan.
Blood.
Darah.
i smell blood.
Aku mencium bau darah.
Let me rip you.
Biarkan aku mencabikmu.
Let me kill you.
Biarkan aku membunuhmu.
Kilt
Bunuh!
-KGHE -Harry!
Harry!
-Did you hear it? -Hear what?
Kalian dengar itu?! Dengar apa?
-That voice. -Voice? What voice?
Suara itu! Suara? Suara apa?
l heard it first in Lockhart’s office. And then again just--
Pertama kudengar di kantor Lockhart. Lalu barusan lagi...
it’s time.
Sekaranglah waktunya.
It’s moving. I think it’s going to kill.
Suaranya bergerak. Kurasa ia berniat membunuh.
-Kill? -Harry, wait! Not so fast!
Membunuh?! Harry, tunggu! Jangan cepat-cepat!
Strange.
Aneh.
-I've never seen spiders act like that. -I don't like spiders.
Tak pernah lihat laba-laba bersikap begitu!Aku tak suka laba-laba.
What's that?
Apa itu?
“The Chamber of Secrets has been opened. Enemies of the Heir, beware.”
“Kamar Rahasia sudah dibuka. Musuh Sang Pewaris, waspadalah."
It’s written in blood.
Ditulis dengan darah.
Oh, no.
Oh, tidak.
It’s Filch’s cat.
Itu kucing Filch.
It’s Mrs. Norris.
Itu Ny. Norris.
“Enemies of the Heir, beware.”
“Musuh Sang Pewaris, waspadalah."
You'll be next, Mudbloods.
Berikutnya kau, Darah-lumpur.
What's going on here? Go on. Make way, make way.
Ada apa di sini? Beri jalan.
Potter?
Potter?
What are you...?
Apa yang kau...
Mrs. Norris?
Ny. Norris?
-You've murdered my cat. -No. No.
Kau membunuh kucingku! Tidak.
PIL kill you.
Aku akan membunuhmu.
-V'Il kill, you! -Argus!
Aku akan membunuhmu!! Argus!
Argus, l....
Argus, aku...
Everyone will proceed to their dormitories immediately.
Semua harus segera ke asrama.
Everyone except...
Semua kecuali...
..-you three.
..kalian bertiga.
Ravenclaws, follow me.
Ikuti aku, Ravenclaws.
She's not dead, Argus. She has been Petrified.
la belum mati, Argus. la hanya dibuat membatu.
Thought so. So unlucky I wasn’t there.
Sudah kuduga. Sayang sekali aku tak di sana.
I know exactly the countercurse that could've spared her.
Aku tahu persis mantra balasan yang bisa menyelamatkannya.
But how she has been Petrified, I cannot say.
Tapi bagaimana ia bisa dibatukan, aku tak tahu.
Ask him. It’s him that’s done it.
Tanya padanya. la yang melakukannya.
You saw what he wrote on the wall.
Profesor lihat tulisannya di dinding.
It’s not true, sir. 1 swear. I never touched Mrs. Norris.
Itu tidak benar. Aku bersumpah. Aku tak menyentuh Ny. Norris.
-Rubbish. -If l might, headmaster?
Bohong! Aku boleh bicara, Kepala Sekolah?
Perhaps Potter and his friends were simply in the wrong place at the wrong time.
Mungkin Potter dan teman-temannya ada di tempat dan waktu tak tepat.
However...
Namun...
...the circumstances are suspicious.
..kejadian ini mencurigakan.
I, for one, don’t recall seeing Potter at dinner.
Aku tak ingat melihat Potter di ruang makan.
I'm afraid that’s my doing, Severus.
Sayang sekali aku penyebabnya, Severus.
You see, Harry was helping me answer my fan mail.
Harry menolongku menjawab surat-surat penggemarku.
That's why Ron and I went looking for him, professor.
Karena itulah Ron dan aku mencarinya, Profesor.
We'd just found him when he said....
Kami baru saja bertemu dengannya waktu ia mengatakan...
-Yes, Miss Granger? -When I said 1 wasn't hungry.
Ya, Nona Granger?! Waktu kukatakan aku tak lapar.
We were heading back to the common room when we found Mrs. Norris.
Kami sedang ke ruang rekreasi waktu kami menemukan Ny. Norris.
-Innocent until proven guilty, Severus. -My cat has been Petrified.
Tak bersalah sampai terbukti! Kucingku dibuat membatu.
-l want to see some punishment! -We will be able to cure her, Argus.
Aku ingin pelakunya dihukum!! Kita bisa menyembuhkannya, Argus.
As I understand it, Madam Sprout has a very healthy growth of Mandrake.
Setahuku, Ny. Sprout punya tanaman Mandrake yang subur sekali.
When matured, a potion will be made which will revive Mrs. Norris.
Jika sudah besar, akan dibuatkan untuk menyembuhkan Ny. Norris.
And in the meantime...
Dan sementara itu...
... 1 strongly recommend caution...
..kuperintahkan semua untuk...
...to all.
..waspada.
-It’s a bit strange, isn’t it? -Strange?
Agak aneh, bukan?! Aneh?
You hear this voice, a voice only you can hear...
Kau dengar suara itu, dan hanya kau yang bisa dengar.
...and then Mrs. Norris turns up Petrified. It’s just strange.
Lalu Ny. Norris membatu. Itu aneh.
Do you think I should have told them? Dumbledore and the others, I mean?
Menurutmu seharusnya kuceritakan pada Dumbledore dan yang lainnya?
Are you mad?
Kau gila?
No, Harry. Even in the wizarding world, hearing voices isn’t a good sign.
Tidak. Di dunia sihirpun, mendengar suara-suara itu pertanda buruk.
She's right, you know.
la benar.
Could I have your attention, please?
Tolong perhatiannya.
Right. Now, today, we will be transforming animals...
Baiklah. Hari ini kita akan mengubah hewan...
...into water goblets.
..menjadi tempat minum.
Like so.
Seperti ini.
One, two, three. Vera Verto.
Satu, dua, tiga. Vera Verto.
Now it’s your turn. Who would like to go first?
Sekarang giliran kalian. Siapa yang ingin duluan?
Mr. Weasley. "One, two, three. Vera Verto.”
Tn. Weasley. “Satu, dua, tiga. Vera Verto."
Vera Verto!
Vera Verto!
That wand needs replacing, Mr. Weasley.
Tongkat itu harus diganti, Tn. Weasley.
-Yes, Miss Granger? -Professor...
Ya, Nn. Granger?! Profesor,...
...l was wondering if you could tell us about the Chamber of Secrets.
..aku ingin tahu apakah Ibu bisa ceritakan tentang Kamar Rahasia?
Very well.
Baiklah.
You all know, of course...
Kalian semua tentu saja tahu...
...that Hogwarts was founded over a thousand years ago...
...Hogwarts didirikan lebih dari seribu tahun yang lalu...
...by the four greatest witches and wizards of the age:
..oleh penyihir-penyihir terbaik masa itu.
Godric Gryffindor, Helga Hufflepuff...
Godric Gryffindor, Helga Hufflepuff...
...Rowena Ravenclaw and Salazar Slytherin.
...Rowena Ravenclaw dan Salazar Slytherin.
Now, three of the founders coexisted quite harmoniously.
Tiga dari pendirinya hidup berdampingan cukup baik.
-One did not. -Three guesses who.
Salah satunya tidak! Tiga tebakan siapa.
Salazar Slytherin wished to be more selective...
Salazar Slytherin ingin lebih selektif...
...about the students admitted to Hogwarts.
..mengenai murid-murid yang akan diterima di Hogwarts.
He believed magical learning should be kept within all-magic families.
la yakin sihir harus dipelajari hanya oleh keluarga penyihir.
In other words, pure-bloods.
Dengan kata lain, yang berdarah murni.
Unable to sway the others, he decided to leave the school.
Tak bisa meyakinkan yang lain, ia putuskan meninggalkan sekolah.
Now, according to legend...
Menurut legenda...
...Slytherin had built a hidden chamber in this castle...
...Siytherin membangun kamar rahasia di kastil ini...
...known as the Chamber of Secrets.
...yang dikenal dengan nama Kamar Rahasia.
Though, shortly before departing, he sealed it...
Tapi, tak lama sebelum pergi, ia menutupnya...
.-until that time when his own true Heir returned to the school.
...sSampai keturunan murninya kembali ke sekolah itu.
The Heir alone...
Hanya keturunan itulah...
..-would be able to open the Chamber...
...yang bisa membuka Kamar Rahasia...
...and unleash the horror within, and by so doing...
...dan membebaskan iblis di dalamnya, dan untuk...
...purge the school of all those who...
membersihkan sekolah dari - - siapa saja yang...
...in Slytherin’s view, were unworthy to study magic.
..menurut pandangan Slytherin tak layak mempelajari ilmu sihir.
Muggle-borns.
Kelahiran Muggle.
Naturally, the school has been searched many times.
Tentu saja, sekolah telah mencarinya berkali-kali.
No such chamber has been found.
Kamar itu tak pernah ditemukan.
Professor? What exactly does legend tell us lies within the Chamber?
Apa sebenarnya yang ada di Kamar itu menurut legenda?
The Chamber is said to be home to something...
Kamar itu katanya menjadi rumah mahluk...
...that only the Heir of Slytherin can control.
...yang hanya bisa dikendalikan keturunan Slytherin.
It is said to be the home...
Menurut legenda, itu adalah rumah...
...of a monster.
...dari monster.
Do you think it’s true? Do you think there really is a Chamber of Secrets?
Benarkah itu? Menurutmu Kamar Rahasia itu ada?
Yes. Couldn't you tell? McGonagall’s worried. All the teachers are.
Ya. Kau tak tahu? McGonagall cemas. Semua guru di sini cemas.
If there really is a Chamber of Secrets, and it really has been opened, that means--
Jika Kamar itu benar ada, dan jika telah dibuka, itu artinya...
The Heir of Slytherin has returned to Hogwarts. The question is, who is it?
Pewaris Slytherin telah kembali ke Hograwts. Pertanyaannya, siapa?
Let's think. Who do we know who thinks all Muggle-borns are scum?
Coba pikir. Siapa menurut kita yang menghina keturunan Muggle?
-If you're talking about Malfoy-- -Of course. You heard him.
Kalau menurutmu Malfoy...! Tentu saja. Kau dengar katanya.
"You'll be next, Mudbloods.”
“Kau berikutnya, Darah-lumpur."
l heard him. But Malfoy, the Heir of Slytherin?
Aku dengar. Tapi Malfoy, keturunan Slytherin?
Maybe Ron's right, Hermione. I mean, look at his family.
Mungkin Ron benar, Hermione. Lihat keluarganya.
The whole lot of them have been in Slytherin for centuries.
Mereka semua pernah tinggal di asrama Slytherin.
Crabbe and Goyle must know. Maybe we could trick them into telling.
Crabbe dan Goyle pasti tahu. Kita tipu mereka agar mau beritahu.
Even they aren't that thick. But there might be another way.
Mereka tak sebodoh itu. Tapi mungkin ada cara lain.
Mind you, it would be difficult.
Kuingatkan, itu mungkin sulit.
Not to mention we'd be breaking about 50 school rules...
Apa lagi kita akan melanggar sekitar 50 peraturan sekolah.
..and it'll be dangerous. Very dangerous.
Dan itu akan berbahaya. Sangat berbahaya.
Here it is. The Polyjuice Potion.
Ini dia. Ramuan Polijus.
"Properly brewed, the Polyjuice Potion allows the drinker...
“Jika dimasak dengan benar, akan membuat peminumnya...
...to transform himself temporarily into the physical form of another.”
..mengubah dirinya sementara menjadi orang lain."
You mean if Harry and I drink that stuff, we'll turn into Crabbe and Goyle?
Maksudmu jika meminumnya, kami bisa jadi Crabbe dan Goyle?
-Wicked! Malfoy will tell us anything. -Exactly.
Hebat! Malfoy pasti mengoceh! Tepat sekali.
But it's tricky. I've never seen a more complicated potion.
Tapi sulit sekali. Aku tak pernah lihat ramuan yang serumit ini.
-How long will it take to make? -A month.
Berapa lama membuatnya?! Sebulan.
A month?
Sebulan?
But, Hermione, if Malfoy is the Heir of Slytherin...
Tapi jika Malfoy benar keturunan Slytherin...
..-he could attack half the Muggle-borns in the school by then.
..Ia bisa menyerang separuh keturunan Muggle di sekolah ini.
I know.
Aku tahu.
But it’s the only plan we've got.
Tapi hanya itu rencana yang kita punya.
Another goal for Slytherin!
Gol lagi untuk Slytherin!
They lead Gryffindor 90 to 30.
Mereka memimpin 90-30 melawan Gryffindor.
Yeah!
Ya!
All right there, Scarhead?
Baik-baik saja, Dahi Pitak?
Watch yourself, Harry!
Hati-hati, Harry!
Wood, look out!
Wood, awas!
Blimey! Harry’s got himself a rogue Bludger.
Astaga! Harry diincar Bludger mengamuk.
That's been tampered with, that has.
Pasti sudah bludger itu dikerjai.
Pll stop it.
Aku akan menghentikannya.
No! Even with a proper wand, it’s too risky. You could hit Harry.
Tidak! Pakai tongkat baguspun, tetap berbahaya. Bisa mengenai Harry.
Training for the ballet, Potter?
Latihan balet, Potter?
You'll never catch me, Potter.
Kau tak mungkin bisa mengejarku, Potter.
Let’s go.
Ayo.
Harry Potter has caught the Snitch. Gryffindor wins!
Harry Potter menangkap Snitch. Gryffindor menang!
Finite Incantatem!
Finite Incantatem!
-Thank you. -Are you okay?
Terima kasih! Kau baik-baik saja?
No. I think my arm is broken.
Tidak. Kurasa tanganku patah.
Not to worry, Harry. I will fix that arm of yours straightaway.
Jangan takut, Harry. Aku akan segera menyembuhkan tanganmu.
-Not you. -Boy doesn't know what he’s saying.
Jangan Anda! la tak sadari perkataannya.
This won't hurt a bit.
Ini sama sekali tak akan sakit.
Brackium Emendo!
Brackium Emendo!
Yes, well, that can sometimes happen...
Ya, itu kadang terjadi...
...but the point is...
...tapi intinya adalah...
..-you can no longer feel any pain, and, very clearly, the bones are not broken.
..kau takkan merasa sakit lagi, dan sudah jelas tulangmu tak patah.
Broken? There’s no bones left.
Patah? Tangannya sama sekali tak bertulang.
Much more flexible, though.
Tapi jadi lebih lentur.
Mr. Malfoy, stop making such a fuss. You can go. Out of my way.
Jangan dibesar-besarkan, Malfoy. Kau boleh pergi. Minggir.
Should have been brought straight to me.
Seharusnya ia langsung dibawa kepadaku.
I can mend bones in a heartbeat, but growing them back....
Aku bisa cepat sembuhkan tulang yang patah, tapi menumbuhkannya...
You will be able to, won't you?
Tapi kau bisa, bukan?
I'll be able to, certainly. But it'll be painful.
Tentu saja. Tapi prosesnya menyakitkan.
You're in for a rough night, Potter. Regrowing bones is a nasty business.
Malammu sudah cukup melelahkan. Menumbuhkan tulangmu sulit sekali.
What do you expect? Pumpkin juice?
Apa yang kauharapkan? Jus labu?
Kill.
Bunuh.
Time to kill.
Sekarang saatnya.
Hello.
Halo.
Dobby?
Dobby?
Harry Potter should have listened to Dobby.
Seharusnya Harry Potter mendengarkan kata Dobby.
Harry Potter should have gone back home when he missed the train.
Seharusnya Harry pulang ke rumah waktu ketinggalan kereta.
It was you. You stopped the barrier from letting Ron and me through.
Kau. Kau yang menutup palang penghalang tempat Ron dan aku lewat.
Indeed. Yes, sir.
Tepat sekali. Benar, Tuan.
-You nearly got Ron and me expelled. -At least you would be away from here.
Kau hampir buat kami dikeluarkan! Setidaknya kau menjauh dari sini.
Harry Potter must go home.
Harry Potter harus pulang.
Dobby thought his Bludger would be enough to make Harry Potter see--
Dobby pikir Bludger-nya cukup untuk menyadarkan Harry Potter.
Your Bludger? You made that Bludger chase after me?
Bludger-mu? Kau yang membuat Bludger itu mengejarku?
Dobby feels most aggrieved, sir.
Dobby merasa sedih sekali, Tuan.
Dobby had to iron his hands.
Dobby sampai menyeterika tangannya.
You better clear off before my bones come back, Dobby, or I might strangle you.
Pergilah sebelum tulangku tumbuh. Atau kucekik kau.
Dobby is used to death threats, sir. Dobby gets them five times a day at home.
Dobby biasa diancam dibunuh, Tuan. Lima kali sehari di rumah.
I don’t suppose you could tell me why you're trying to kill me?
Kenapa kau mencoba membunuhku?
Not kill you, sir. Never kill you.
Bukan membunuh Tuan. Tak pernah berniat membunuh Tuan.
Dobby remembers how it was before Harry Potter triumphed...
Dobby ingat bagaimana sebelum kemenangan Harry Potter...
...over He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named.
..melawan Dia-Yang-Tak-Boleh- Disebut-Namanya.
We house-elves were treated like vermin, sir.
Peri-rumah diperlakukan seperti hama, Tuan.
Of course, Dobby is still treated like vermin.
Tentu saja, Dobby masih diperlakukan seperti hama.
Why do you wear that thing, Dobby?
Kenapa kau memakai baju seperti itu, Dobby?
This, sir? It is a mark of the house-elf’s enslavement.
Ini? Ini tanda penghambaan peri-rumah.
Dobby can only be freed if his master presents him with clothes.
Dobby hanya bisa dibebaskan oleh baju pemberian tuannya.
Listen.
Dengar.
Listen!
Dengar!
Terrible things are about to happen at Hogwarts.
Di Hogwarts akan terjadi hal yang mengerikan.
Harry Potter must not stay here...
Harry Potter tak boleh tinggal di sini...
...now that history is to repeat itself.
..karena sejarah akan terulang.
Repeat itself? You mean this has happened before?
Terulang? Maksudmu ini pernah terjadi?
I shouldn't have said that.
Aku seharusnya tak boleh mengatakannya.
-Bad Dobby! Bad! -Stop it!
Dobby nakal! Nakal!! Hentikan!
Stop it, Dobby!
Hentikan, Dobby!
Tell me. When did this happen before? Who's doing it now?
Kapan ini pernah terjadi? Siapa yang melakukannya sekarang?
Dobby cannot say, sir. Dobby only wants Harry Potter to be safe.
Dobby tak bisa bilang, Tuan. Dobby hanya ingin Harry selamat.
No, Dobby. Tell me. Who is it?
Tidak, Dobby. Katakan padaku. Siapa yang membukanya?
Put him here.
Baringkan dia di sini.
-What happened? -There’s been another attack.
Ada apa?! Ada serangan baru.
I think he’s been Petrified, Madam Pomfrey.
Sepertinya ia dibuat membatu, Madam Pomfrey.
Look. Perhaps he managed to take a picture of his attacker.
Lihat. Mungkin ia berhasil memotret pelakunya.
What can this mean, Albus?
Pertanda apa ini, Albus?
It means...
Ini pertanda...
...that our students are in great danger.
...kalau murid-murid kita dalam bahaya besar.
-What should I tell the staff? -The truth.
Harus kuceritakan apa para staf?! Yang sebenarnya.
Tell them Hogwarts is no longer safe.
Katakan bahwa Hogwarts tak lagi aman.
It is as we feared, Minerva.
Ini seperti yang kita takutkan, Minerva.
The Chamber of Secrets has indeed been opened again.
Kamar Rahasia sudah dibuka kembali.
Again? You mean the Chamber of Secrets has been opened before?
Kembali? Maksudmu Kamar Rahasia pernah dibuka?
Of course. Don't you see?
Tentu saja. Kau tak mengerti?
Lucius Malfoy must have opened it when he was at school here.
Lucius Malfoy pasti pernah membukanya saat ia sekolah di sini.
-Now he’s taught Draco how to do it. -Maybe.
Sekarang ia mengajari Draco! Mungkin.
We'll have to wait for the Polyjuice Potion to know for sure.
Kita harus menunggu Ramuan Polijus untuk memastikannya.
Enlighten me. Why are we brewing this potion in broad daylight...
Kenapa kita merebus ramuan ini di siang bolong...
...in the middle of the girls’ lavatory? Don't you think we'll get caught?
...Gi toilet wanita? Kau yakin kita takkan ketahuan?
No. No one ever comes in here.
Tidak. Tak ada yang pernah ke sini.
-Why? -Moaning Myrtle.
Kenapa?! Myrtle Merana.
Who?
Siapa?
-Who’s Moaning Myrtle? -I’m Moaning Myrtle.
Siapa dia?! Aku Myrtle Merana.
I wouldn't expect you to know me.
Aku tak mengharapkan kau kenal aku.
Who would ever talk about ugly, miserable...
Siapa yang ingin membicarakan Mrytle Merana yang...
...moping Moaning Myrtle?
..jelek dan menyedihkan?
She's a little sensitive.
la mudah tersinggung.
Gather round!
Berkumpullah!
Gather round. Can everybody see me?
Berkumpullah. Semua bisa melihatku?
Can you all hear me?
Semua bisa mendengarku?
Excellent.
Bagus.
In light of the dark events of recent weeks...
Karena kejadian-kejadian mengerikan belakangan ini,...
...Professor Dumbledore has granted me permission to start this Dueling Club...
...Profesor Dumbledore mengijinkanku membuat Klub Duel...
...to train you all up in case you ever need to defend yourselves...
..untuk melatih kalian semua jika kalian harus mempertahankan diri.
...as I myself have done on countless occasions.
Seperti yang kulakukan dalam berbagai kejadian.
For full details, see my published works.
Untuk detilnya, silakan lihat buku-bukuku.
Let me introduce my assistant...
Kuperkenalkan asistenku...
...Professor Snape.
..Professor Snape.
He has sportingly agreed to help with a short demonstration.
la bersedia untuk membantuku memberi demonstrasi singkat.
I don’t want any of you youngsters to worry.
Kalian tak perlu khawatir.
You'll still have your Potions master when I’m through with him. Never fear.
Kalian masih punya guru Ramuan setelah duel ini. Jangan takut.
One.
Satu.
Two.
Dua.
-Three! -Expelliarmus!
Tiga!! Expelliarmus!
-Do you think he’s all right? -Who cares?
la baik-baik saja?! Siapa yang peduli?
An excellent idea to show them that, Professor Snape...
Ide hebat untuk menunjukkan gerakan itu pada mereka, Profesor Snape.
...but if you don’t mind me saying, it was pretty obvious what you were about to do.
Tapi, jika boleh kukatakan ini, tindakanmu tadi sudah terbaca jelas.
If ! had wanted to stop you, it would have been only too easy.
Terlalu mudah kalau aku ingin menghentikanmu.
Perhaps it would be prudent to first teach the students...
Mungkin lebih baik mengajarkan pada murid-murid...
...to block unfriendly spells, professor.
..untuk menahan serangan mantra musuh, profesor.
An excellent suggestion, Professor Snape.
Saran yang baik sekali, Profesor Snape.
Let's have a volunteer pair. Potter, Weasley, how about you?
Kita cari pasangan sukarela. Potter, Weasley, silakan.
Weasley’s wand causes devastation with the simplest spells.
Tongkat Weasley bisa mencelakakan meski dengan mantra sederhana.
We'll be sending Potter to the hospital wing in a matchbox.
Nanti kita harus memasukkan Potter ke ruang rawat dalam kotak korek.
Might I suggest someone from my own house?
Aku boleh sarankan siswa dari asramaku?
Malfoy, perhaps?
Mungkin Malfoy?
-Good luck, Potter. -Thank you, sir.
Semoga berhasil, Potter) Terima kasih.
Wands at the ready.
Siapkan tongkat sihir kalian.
-Scared, Potter? -You wish.
Takut, Potter?) Enak saja.
On the count of three...
Di hitungan ke tiga...
...cast your charms to disarm your opponent. Only to disarm.
..Siapkan mantra untuk melucuti senjata lawanmu.
We don’t want any accidents here. One.
Kita tak ingin terjadi kecelakaan di sini. Satu.
-Two. -Everte Statum!
Dua! Everte Statum!
Rictusempra!
Rictusempra!
l said disarm only.
Kubilang hanya untuk melucuti.
Serpensortia!
Serpensortia!
Don’t move, Potter. Il get rid of it for you.
Jangan bergerak, Potter. Aku akan menyingkirkannya.
Allow me, Professor Snape. Alarte Ascendare!
Biar aku saja, Profesor Snape. Alarte Ascendare!
Vipera Evanesca.
Vipera Evanesca.
What are you playing at?
Apa yang kaulakukan?
You're a Parselmouth? Why didn’t you tell us?
Kau Parselmouth? Kenapa tak bilang pada kami?
-I'm a what? -You can talk to snakes.
Aku apa?! Kau bisa bicara dengan ular.
I know. I accidentally set a python on my cousin Dudley at the zoo once.
Aku tahu. Aku pernah melepas ular ke tubuh Dudley di kebun binatang.
Once. But so what? I bet loads of people here can do it.
Hanya sekali. Tapi memang kenapa? Pasti banyak juga yang bisa.
No, they can’t. It’s not a very common gift, Harry.
Tidak. Itu bukan bakat yang biasa, Harry.
This is bad.
Ini pertanda buruk.
What's bad? If I hadn't told that snake not to attack Justin--
Apanya? Kalau aku tak melarang ular itu menyerang Justin...
-That’s what you said to it. -You were there. You heard me.
Itu perintahmu padanya?! Kau di sana. Kau dengar ucapanku.
l heard you speaking Parseltongue. Snake language.
Aku dengar kau bicara Parseltongue. Itu bahasa ular.
I spoke a different language?
Aku bicara bahasa lain?
But I didn’t realize--
Tapi aku tak menyadari...
How can I speak a language without knowing I can?
Mana mungkin aku bisa bicara bahasa lain tanpa menyadarinya?
I don’t know, but it sounded like you were egging the snake on or something.
Entahlah. Tapi sepertinya kau berhasil mempengaruhi ular itu.
Harry, listen to me.
Dengarkan aku, Harry.
There’s a reason the symbol of Slytherin house is a serpent.
Ada alasan kenapa simbol di asrama Slytherin berbentuk ular.
Salazar Slytherin was a Parselmouth. He could talk to snakes too.
Salazar Slytherin juga Parselmouth. la juga bisa berbicara dengan ular.
Exactly.
Tepat sekali.
Now the whole school’s gonna think you're his great-great-great grandson.
Sekarang seluruh sekolah akan mengira kau keturunannya.
But I’m not.
Tapi aku bukan keturunannya.
I can’t be.
Tak mungkin aku.
He lived a thousand years ago.
la hidup beribu tahun yang lalu.
For all we know, you could be.
Yang kami tahu, kau mungkin saja keturunannya.
I'll see you back in the common room.
Kutunggu kalian di ruang rekreasi.
! want blood.
Aku ingin darah.
They all must die.
Mereka semua harus mati.
Kill.
Bunuh.
Time to kill.
Saatnya membunuh.
Caught in the act.
Tertangkap basah.
I'll have you out this time, Potter.
Aku akan membuatmu dikeluarkan kali ini, Potter.
Mark my words.
Catat kata-kataku.
No. Mr. Filch! You don’t understand--
Tidak. Tn. Filch! Kau tak mengerti...
Professor...
Profesor.
... swear I didn’t.
Aku bersumpah bukan aku pelakunya.
This is out of my hands, Potter.
Ini di luar kendaliku, Potter.
Professor Dumbledore will be waiting for you.
Profesor Dumbledore menunggumu di sana.
Sherbet Lemon.
Permen lemon.
Professor Dumbledore?
Profesor Dumbledore?
Bee in your bonnet, Potter?
Tergoda untuk coba lagi, Potter?
I was just wondering if you put me in the right house.
Aku hanya ingin tahu apakah aku ditempatkan di asrama yang tepat.
Yes. You were particularly difficult to place.
Ya. Cukup sulit mencari tempat yang tepat untukmu.
But I stand by what I said last year.
Tapi perkataanku tahun lalu tetap sama.
You would have done well in Slytherin.
Kau akan sukses di Slytherin.
You're wrong.
Kau salah.
Harry?
Harry?
Professor.
Professor.
Your bird.... There was nothing I could do.
Burung profesor... Aku tak bisa berbuat apa-apa.
-He just caught fire. -And about time too.
la terbakar api! Dan sudah saatnya juga.
He’s been looking dreadful for days.
la sudah berhari-hari kelihatan sakit.
Pity you had to see him on a burning day.
Sayang sekali kau harus melihatnya saat ia hangus.
Fawkes is a phoenix, Harry.
Fawkes adalah burung Phoenix.
They burst into flame when it is time for them to die...
Mereka akan terbakar jika sudah waktunya mereka mati.
...and then they are...
Dan mereka akan...
...reborn from the ashes.
...Tahir kembali dari abunya.
Fascinating creatures, phoenixes.
Burung Phoenix memang hebat.
They can carry immensely heavy loads.
Mereka bisa membawa beban berat.
Their tears have healing powers.
Air mata mereka punya kekuatan untuk menyembuhkan.
Professor Dumbledore, sir! Wait! Listen!
Profesor Dumbledore! Tunggu! Dengar!
Professor Dumbledore, sir, it wasn’t Harry.
Profesor Dumbledore, bukan Harry pelakunya.
I'd be prepared to swear it in front of the Ministry of Magic.
Aku bersedia bersumpah di depan Kementrian Sihir.
Relax.
Tenang.
I do not believe...
Aku tak percaya...
-...that Harry attacked anyone. -Of course you don't.
...Harry mampu menyakiti orang! Tentu saja.
Right. Well, l'll....
Benar. Aku akan...
-I'll just wait outside, then. -Yes.
Kalau begitu aku akan keluar! Ya.
-You don't think it was me, professor? -No, Harry.
Menurut Profesor bukan aku?! Bukan, Harry.
I do not think it was you.
Menurutku pelakunya bukan kau.
But I must ask you...
Tapi aku harus bertanya padamu...
..is there something you wish to tell me?
..adakah sesuatu yang ingin kau beritahu padaku?
No, sir.
Tidak, Pak.
Nothing.
Tak ada.
Very well, then.
Baiklah, kalau begitu.
Off you go.
Kau boleh pergi.
Everything's set. We just need a bit of who you're changing into.
Semua siap. Hanya perlu bagian tubuh orang yang ingin kautiru.
Crabbe and Goyle.
Crabbe dan Goyle.
We also need to make sure that the real Crabbe and Goyle...
Kita juga harus memastikan Crabbe dan Goyle yang asli...
..-can’t burst in on us while we're interrogating Malfoy.
...tak mengganggu kita sementara kita menginterogasi Malfoy.
-How? -I’ve got it all worked out.
Bagaimana?! Aku sudah merencanakannya.
I filled these with a simple Sleeping Draught.
Aku mengisi ini dengan Ramuan Tidur sederhana.
Simple, but powerful.
Sederhana, tapi manjur.
Now, once they're asleep...
Sekarang, begitu mereka tidur...
..-hide them in the broomstick cupboard and pull out a few of their hairs...
..sembunyikan mereka di lemari kebersihan, ambil sehelai rambut.
..-and put on their uniforms.
Dan pakai seragam mereka.
-Whose hair are you ripping out, then? -I’ve already got mine.
Rambut siapa yang akan kauambil?! Aku sudah mengambilnya.
Millicent Bulstrode. Slytherin.
Millicent Bulstrode. Slytherin.
I got this off her robes.
Aku dapat ini dari bajunya.
I'm going to go check on the Polyjuice Potion.
Aku akan memeriksa Ramuan Polijus-nya.
Make sure that Crabbe and Goyle find these.
Pastikan Crabbe dan Goyle menemukan ini.
Ron, maybe ! should do it.
Aku saja yang melakukannya, Ron.
Yeah. Right.
Ya. Benar.
Wingardium Leviosa.
Wingardium Leviosa.
Cool.
Asyik.
How thick could you get?
Yang begitu dibilang cukup pintar?
Come on, let’s get them.
Ayo, kita sembunyikan mereka.
We'll have exactly one hour before we change back into ourselves.
Kita punya waktu sejam sebelum berubah menjadi diri kita lagi.
Add the hairs.
Tambahkan rambut mereka.
Essence of Crabbe.
Saripati Crabbe.
Cheers.
Mari bersulang.
I think I'm gonna be sick.
Aku rasanya ingin muntah.
Me too.
Aku juga.
Harry?
Harry?
Ron.
Ron.
Bloody hell!
Ya, ampun!
We still sound like ourselves.
Suara kita masih sama.
You need to sound more like Crabbe.
Kau harus bersuara seperti Crabbe.
-Bloody hell. -Excellent.
Ya, ampun! Bagus.
-But where's Hermione? che.
Tapi di mana Hermione?
I don’t think I'm going. You go on without me.
Aku tak akan ikut. Kalian pergilah tanpa aku.
Hermione, are you okay?
Kau baik-baik saja, Hermione?
Just go. You're wasting time.
Pergilah. Kalian membuang waktu.
Come on.
Ayo.
I think the Slytherin common room's this way.
Sepertinya ruang rekreasi Slytherin ada di sini.
Excuse me.
Maaf.
What are you doing d--?
Apa yang kaulakukan...
I mean, what are you doing down here?
Maksudku, apa yang kaulakukan di sini?
I happen to be a school prefect.
Kebetulan aku adalah Prefek.
You, on the other hand, have no business wandering the corridors at night.
Sebaliknya kalian tak boleh berkeliaran di koridor malam-malam.
What are your names again?
Siapa nama kalian?
-I'm.... -Crabbe, Goyle, where have you two been?
Aku... Crabbe, Goyle. Dari mana kalian?
Pigging out in the Great Hall all this time?
Kalian dari tadi mengunyah terus di Aula Besar?
Why are you wearing glasses?
Kenapa kau memakai kaca mata?
-Reading. -Reading?
Membaca! Membaca?
I didn’t know you could read.
Aku tak tahu kau bisa membaca.
And what are you doing down here, Weasley?
Dan kenapa kau di sini, Weasley?
Mind your attitude, Malfoy.
Jaga sikapmu, Malfoy.
Well, sit down.
Duduklah.
You'd never know the Weasleys were pure-bloods, the way they behave.
Tak ada yang menyangka Weasley berdarah murni, dari sikap mereka.
They're an embarrassment to the wizarding world. All of them.
Mereka semua memalukan dunia sihir.
What's wrong with you, Crabbe?
Kenapa kau, Crabbe?
Stomachache.
Sakit perut.
You know, I’m surprised the Daily Prophet hasn't done a report on all these attacks.
Aku heran Daily Prophet tak melaporkan serangan ini.
l suppose Dumbledore is trying to hush it all up.
Pasti Dumbledore mencoba merahasiakannya.
Father always said Dumbledore was the worst thing...
Ayah selalu mengatakan Dumbledore adalah yang terburuk...
-...that ever happened to this place. -You’re wrong!
...di tempat ini! Kau salah!
What?
Apa?
You think there’s someone here who's worse than Dumbledore?
Menurutmu ada yang lebih buruk dari Dumbledore?
Well? Do you?
Ada?
Harry Potter?
Harry Potter?
Good one, Goyle.
Bagus, Goyle.
You're absolutely right.
Kau benar sekali.
Saint Potter.
Santo Potter.
And people actually think that he’s the Heir of Slytherin?
Dan orang menganggap dia keturunan Slytherin?
But then you must have some idea who's behind it all.
Tapi kalau begitu kau tahu siapa dalangnya.
You know I don’t, Goyle. Il told you yesterday.
Aku tak tahu, Goyle. Aku sudah bilang kemarin padamu.
How many times do I have to tell you?
Berapa kali aku harus memberitahumu?
Is this yours?
Ini punyamu?
But my father did say this:
Tapi ayahku bilang begini...
It’s been 50 years since the Chamber was opened.
50 tahun berselang sejak Kamar Rahasia dibuka.
He wouldn't tell me who opened it. Only that they were expelled.
la tak memberitahu siapa. Hanya bilang mereka dikeluarkan.
The last time the Chamber of Secrets was opened, a Mudblood died.
Terakhir Kamar Rahasia dibuka, seorang Darah-lumpur tewas.
So it’s only a matter of time before one of them is killed this time.
Jadi tinggal tunggu waktu sebelum salah satunya terbunuh kali ini.
As for me...
Dan bagiku...
...[ hope it’s Granger.
..kuharap orangnya Granger.
What's the matter with you two?
Kenapa kalian berdua?
You're acting very odd.
Kalian bertingkah aneh sekali.
It’s his stomachache.
Pasti karena sakit perutnya.
Calm down.
Tenanglah.
Scar.
Bekas lukamu.
Hair.
Rambutmu.
Hey! Where are you going?
Kalian mau ke mana?
That was close.
Nyaris sekali.
Hermione, come out. We've got loads to tell you.
Keluarlah, Hermione. Kami punya banyak berita untukmu.
Go away.
Pergilah.
Wait till you see. It’s awful.
Tunggu sampai kalian melihatnya. Mengerikan sekali.
Hermione?
Hermione?
Are you okay?
Kau baik-baik saja?
Do you remember me telling you...
Kalian ingat aku mengatakan...
...that the Polyjuice Potion was only for human transformations?
..bahwa Polijus hanya untuk mengubah diri menjadi manusia?
It was cat hair I plucked off Millicent Bulstrode’s robes.
Ternyata yang kuambil dari jubah Millicent adalah bulu kucing.
Look at my face.
Lihat mukaku.
Look at your tail.
Lihat ekormu.
Have you spoken to Hermione?
Kau sudah bicara dengan Hermione?
She should be out of hospital in a few days...
la akan keluar dari rumah sakit dalam beberapa hari...
...when she stops coughing up fur balls.
..jika ia sudah berhenti memuntahkan bola bulu.
What's this?
Apa ini?
Yuck!
lih!
Looks like Moaning Myrtle’s flooded the bathroom.
Sepertinya Myrtle Merana menggenangi kamar mandi.
-Come to throw something else at me? -Why would I throw something at you?
Kalian ingin melempariku lagi?! Untuk apa kami melakukannya?
Don't ask me. Here I am, minding my own business...
Jangan tanya aku. Aku di sini, sibuk sendiri...
...-and someone thinks it’s funny to throw a book at me.
..dan ada yang menganggap lucu Jika melempar buku padaku.
But it can’t hurt if someone throws something at you.
Tapi jika ada yang melemparmu, kau takkan terluka.
I mean, it'll just go tight through you.
Maksudku, buku itu akan menembusmu.
Sure! Let’s all throw books at Myrtle because she can't feel it.
Tentu saja! Lempari saja buku ke Myrtle karena ia tak merasakan.
Ten points if you get it through her stomach!
Sepuluh nilai kalau kau bisa melemparkan melewati perutnya.
Fifty points if it goes through her head!
Lima puluh nilai kalau kau bisa melempari kepalanya!
-But who threw it at you, anyway? -I don’t know. I didn’t see them.
Tapi siapa yang melemparimu?! Entah. Aku tak lihat.
I was just sitting in the U-bend, thinking about death...
Aku sedang duduk-duduk di WC, memikirkan kematian...
..and it fell through the top of my head.
..dan buku itu menjatuhi kepalaku.
"Tom Marvolo Riddle.”
“Tom Marvolo Riddle."
My name...
Namaku...
...is Harry...
..Harry...
...Potter.
...Potter.
Do you know anything...
Kau tahu sesuatu...
...about the Chamber of Secrets?
...tentang Kamar Rahasia?
Can you...
Bisakah kau...
..-tell me?
..memberitahuku?
Excuse me. Could you tell me what’s going on here?
Maaf. Bisa beritahu aku apa yang terjadi di sini?
Are you Tom Riddle?
Kau Tom Riddle?
Hello, can you hear me?
Halo, kau bisa mendengarku?
Riddle!
Riddle!
Come.
Kemarilah.
Professor Dumbledore.
Profesor Dumbledore.
Dumbledore?
Dumbledore?
It is not wise to be wandering around this late hour, Tom.
Tak baik berkeliaran malam-malam begini, Tom.
Yes, professor. 1 suppose l....
Ya, Profesor. Kurasa aku...
l had to see for myself if the rumors were true.
Aku harus membuktikan sendiri Jika kabar burung itu benar.
I'm afraid they are, Tom. They are true.
Sayang sekali itu benar, Tom.
About the school as well? I don’t have a home to go to.
Tentang sekolah ini juga? Aku tak punya rumah untuk pulang.
They wouldn't really close Hogwarts, would they, professor?
Hogwarts tak benar-benar ditutup, bukan?
l understand, Tom, but I’m afraid...
Aku mengerti, Tom. Tapi sayangnya...
... Headmaster Dippet may have no choice.
..Kepala Sekolah Dippet tak punya pilihan lain.
Sir, if it all stopped, if the person responsible was caught....
Jika ini semua berhenti, Jika pelakunya tertangkap...
Is there something...
Apakah ada sesuatu...
..-you wish to tell me?
...yang ingin kau katakan padaku?
No, sir. Nothing.
Tidak, Pak. Tak ada.
Very well, then. Off you go.
Baiklah, kalau begitu. Pergilah.
Good night, sir.
Selamat malam, Pak.
-Let’s get you out of there. -Evening, Hagrid.
Kau boleh keluar dari sana! Selamat malam, Hagrid.
I'm going to have to turn you in, Hagrid. I don't think you meant it to kill anyone....
Aku harus menyerahkanmu, Hagrid. Kurasa kau tak ingin ia membunuh.
You can’t. You don’t understand.
Jangan. Kau tak mengerti.
The dead girl's parents will be here tomorrow. The least Hogwarts can do...
Orang tua gadis itu akan datang. Setidaknya Hogwarts harus bisa...
...is make sure the thing that killed their daughter is slaughtered.
..memastikan pembunuh puterinya sudah mati.
It wasn’t him. Aragog never killed no one. Never.
Bukan dia pelakunya. Aragog tak pernah membunuh siapapun.
Monsters don’t make good pets, Hagrid.
Monster bukan hewan peliharaan yang baik, Hagrid.
-Now, stand aside. -No!
Sekarang, minggir! Tidak!
-Stand aside, Hagrid.
Minggir, Hagrid7
Cistem Aperio!
Cistem Aperio!
Arania Exumai!
Arania Exumai!
Aragog!
Aragog!
I can’t let you go.
Aku tak bisa membiarkanmu lolos.
They'll have your wand for this, Hagrid. You'll be expelled.
Mereka akan menyita tongkatmu. Kau akan dikeluarkan.
Hagrid!
Hagrid!
It was Hagrid. Hagrid opened the Chamber of Secrets 50 years ago.
Hagrid pelakunya. Ia yang membuka Kamar Rahasia 50 tahun yang lalu.
It can’t be Hagrid. It just can’t be.
Tak mungkin Hagrid pelakunya.
We don’t even know this Tom Riddle. He sounds like a dirty, rotten snitch to me.
Kita bahkan tak kenal Tom Riddle. Bagiku ia lebih mirip pengadu licik.
The monster had killed somebody, Ron. What would any of us have done?
Moster itu membunuh orang, Ron. Apa yang harus kita lakukan?
Look, Hagrid’s our friend. Why don’t we just go and ask him about it?
Hagrid teman kita. Kenapa kita tak tanya saja padanya?
That would be a cheerful visit. "Hello, Hagrid.
Itu akan menjadi kunjungan yang menyenangkan. “Halo, Hagrid.
Tell us, have you been setting anything mad and hairy loose in the castle lately?”
Coba ceritakan, kau pernah melepas hewan buas berbulu di kastil?"
Mad and hairy? You wouldn't be talking about me, now, would you?
Buas dan berbulu? Kalian bukan membicarakan aku, 'kan?
No.
Bukan.
What's that you've got, Hagrid?
Apa yang kaubawa, Hagrid?
It’s Flesh-Eating Slug Repellent. For the Mandrakes, you know.
Ini Pembasmi Siput-Pemakan-Daging. Untuk ramuan Mandrake.
Now, according to Professor Sprout, they've still got a bit of growing up to do.
Menurut Profesor Sprout, mereka masih harus dewasa dulu.
But once their acne’s cleared up, we'll be able to chop them up and stew them...
Tapi begitu jerawat mereka bersih, kita bisa merajang dan memasaknya.
..and then we'll get those people down at the hospital un-Petrified.
Dan kita bisa bebaskan korban di rumah sakit yang membatu.
In the meantime, though, you three...
Sementara itu, kalian bertiga...
...had best be looking after yourselves. All right?
..sebaiknya berjaga-jaga. Mengerti?
Hello, Neville.
Halo, Neville.
Harry, I don’t know who did it, but you'd better come.
Harry, aku tak tahu pelakunya, tapi sebaiknya kau ikut aku.
Come on!
Ayo!
It had to be a Gryffindor. Nobody else knows our password.
Pelakunya pasti anak Gryffindor. Tak ada yang tahu kata sandi kita.
Unless it wasn’t a student.
Kecuali ia bukan murid di sini.
Whoever it was, they must have been looking for something.
Siapapun itu, ia pasti mencari sesuatu.
And they found it.
Dan ia menemukannya.
Tom Riddle’s diary is gone.
Buku harian Tom Riddle hilang.
All right, listen up.
Baiklah, dengar.
We play our game, Hufflepuff doesn't stand a chance.
Kalau kita memainkan taktik kita, Hufflepuff tak punya kesempatan.
We're stronger, quicker and smarter.
Kita akan lebih kuat, lebih cepat dan lebih cerdik.
Not to mention they’re dead scared that Harry will Petrify them...
Apalagi mereka akan mati ketakutan Jika Harry membatukan mereka...
-...if they fly anywhere near him. -Well, that too.
..jika mereka terbang mendekat! Itu juga.
Professor McGonagall.
Profesor McGonagall.
-This match has been canceled. -We can’t cancel Quidditch.
Pertandingan dibatalkan! Guidditch tak bisa dibatalkan.
Silence, Wood. You and your teammates will go to Gryffindor Tower. Now.
Diam, Wood. Kalian harus ke Menara Gryffindor. Sekarang.
Potter, you and I will find Mr. Weasley.
Potter, kita berdua harus mencari Tn. Weasley.
There’s something the both of you have to see.
Ada sesuatu yang harus kalian lihat.
Il warn you. This could be a wee bit of a shock.
Kuingatkan pada kalian. Ini akan mengejutkan.
Hermione!
Hermione!
She was found near the library...
la ditemukan dekat perpustakaan...
.. along with this.
a. ...memegang ini.
Does it mean anything to either of you?
Ada artinya buat kalian berdua?
No.
Tidak.
Could I have your attention, please?
Perhatian semuanya!
Because of recent events, these new rules will be put into effect immediately:
Karena kejadian belakangan ini, aturan baru segera diberlakukan.
“All students will return to their house common rooms by 6:00 every evening.
“Setiap siswa harus kembali ke ruang rekreasi jam 6:00 tiap malam.
All students will be escorted to each lesson by a teacher.
Setiap siswa harus didampingi guru ke setiap pelajaran.
No exceptions.”
Tanpa kecuali."
I should tell you this:
Aku harus memberitahukan ini.
Unless the culprit behind these attacks is caught...
Jika pelaku serangan ini tak segera tertangkap,...
...it is likely the school will be closed.
...sepertinya sekolah ini harus ditutup.
We've got to talk to Hagrid, Ron. l can’t believe it’s him...
Kita harus bicara pada Hagrid, Ron. Aku tak percaya dia pelakunya.
...but if he did set the monster loose last time...
Tapi jika benar dia yang melepaskan monster itu dulu...
...he’ll know how to get inside the Chamber of Secrets. That's a start.
..Ia pasti tahu bagaimana cara masuk Kamar Rahasia. Itu awalnya.
But you heard McGonagall.
Tapi kau dengar kata McGonagall.
We're not allowed to leave the tower except for class.
Kita tak boleh meninggalkan menara kecuali ke kelas.
I think it’s time to get my dad’s old cloak out again.
Kurasa kini saatnya mengeluarkan lagi selimut tua ayahku.
Who's there?
Siapa itu?
Hello?
Halo?
-What’s that for? -Nothing. I was expecting....
Untuk apa itu?! Tidak apa. Aku menunggu...
It doesn't matter. Come on in. [ just made a pot of tea.
Itu tak penting. Masuklah. Aku baru membuat sepoci teh.
Hagrid, are you okay?
Kau baik-baik saja, Hagrid?
I'm fine. I'm all right.
Aku baik-baik saja.
Did you hear about Hermione?
Kau dengar kabar tentang Hermione?
Yeah. I heard about that, all right.
Ya. Aku dengar kabarnya.
Look, we have to ask you something.
Kami ingin bertanya sesuatu padamu.
Do you know who's opened the Chamber of Secrets?
Kau tahu siapa yang membuka Kamar Rahasia?
What you had to understand about that is--
Yang harus kau harus mengerti...
Quick, under the cloak.
Cepat, ke bawah selimut.
Don't say a word. Be quiet, both of you.
Jangan berisik. Kalian harus diam.
-Professor Dumbledore, sir. -Good evening, Hagrid.
Profesor Dumbledore! Selamat malam, Hagrid.
I wonder, could we...?
Bisakah kami...
Of course. Come in. Come in.
Tentu saja. Silakan masuk.
That’s Dad’s boss.
Itu bos ayahku.
Cornelius Fudge, Minister of Magic.
Cornelius Fudge, Mentri Sihir.
Bad business, Hagrid, very bad business. Had to come.
Ini masalah buruk sekali, Hagrid. Kami terpaksa ke sini.
Three attacks on Muggle-borns. Things have gone far enough.
Tiga murid kelahiran Muggle diserang. Ini sudah terlalu jauh.
-The Ministry's got to act. -But I never--
Kementrian harus bertindak! Tapi aku tak pernah...
You know I never, professor.
Profesor tahu aku tak mungkin melakukannya.
I want it understood, Cornelius...
Pahamilah, Cornelius.
...that Hagrid...
Bahwa Hagrid...
...-has my full confidence.
..mendapat kepercayaan penuh dariku.
Albus, look, Hagrid’s record is against him.
Albus, dengar. Catatan tentang Hagrid sama sekali tak mendukungnya.
-I’ve got to take him. -Take me?
Aku terpaksa menahannya! Menahanku?
Take me where? Not Azkaban prison.
Menahanku ke mana? Jangan ke penjara Azkaban.
I'm afraid we have no choice, Hagrid.
Kami tak punya pilihan lain, Hagrid.
Already here, Fudge?
Sudah di sini, Fudge?
Good.
Bagus.
What are you doing here? Get out of my house!
Apa yang kaulakukan di sini? Keluar dari rumahku!
Believe me...
Percayalah padaku...
...l take absolutely no pleasure being inside your....
...aku tak suka berada di dalam rumahmu.
You call this a house?
Kau sebut ini rumah?
No.
Tidak.
l simply called up the school and was told the headmaster was here.
Aku menghubungi sekolah dan katanya Kepala Sekolah di sini.
Well, what exactly is it that you want with me?
Apa yang kauinginkan dariku?
The other governors and I have decided it’s time for you to step aside.
Dewan Sekolah dan aku memutuskan bahwa sekarang saatnya kau mundur.
This is an order of suspension.
Ini perintah pengskorsan.
You'll find all 12 signatures on it.
Di situ ada 12 tanda tangan.
I'm afraid we feel you've rather lost your touch.
Rupanya kau sudah kehilangan sentuhanmu.
Well, what, with all these attacks...
Dengan serangan-serangan ini...
...there’ll be no Muggle-borns left at Hogwarts.
...tak ada lagi kelahiran-Muggle yang akan tersisa di Hogwarts.
I can only imagine what an awful loss that would be to the school.
Itu kehilangan besar bagi sekolah.
You can’t take Professor Dumbledore away.
Kau tak boleh menyingkirkan Profesor Dumbledore.
Take him away and the Muggle-borns won't stand a chance.
Kalau ia disingkirkan, kelahiran-Muggle akan habis.
You mark my words, there'll be killings next!
Catat kata-kataku, berikutnya akan terjadi pembunuhan!
You think so?
Menurutmu begitu?
Calm yourself, Hagrid.
Tenang, Hagrid.
If the governors desire my removal...
Jika Dewan Sekolah ingin aku mundur...
...[ will, of course, step aside.
...tentu saja aku akan mundur.
However...
Namun...
..-you will find that help will always be given at Hogwarts...
...bantuan akan selalu diberikan di Hogwarts...
...to those who...
..bagi siapa saja...
ask for it.
...yang mengharapkannya.
Admirable sentiments.
Sentimen yang mengagumkan.
Shall we?
Kita berangkat sekarang?
Fudge.
Fudge.
Come, Hagrid.
Ayo, Hagrid.
Well?
Nah.
If...
Jika...
If anybody was looking for some stuff...
Jika ada yang mencari sesuatu...
...then all they’d have to do would be to follow the spiders.
..mereka harus mengikuti laba-laba.
Yep. That would lead them right.
Ya. Itu akan memandu mereka ke tempat yang tepat.
That's all Il have to say.
Hanya itu yang ingin kukatakan.
And someone will need to feed Fang while I'm away.
Dan harus ada yang memberi makan Fang selama aku pergi.
Good boy.
Anak pintar.
Hagrid’s right.
Hagrid benar.
With Dumbledore gone, there'll be an attack a day.
Jika Dumbledore tak ada, serangan akan terjadi setiap hari.
Look.
Lihat.
Come on.
Ayo.
Come on, Fang.
Ayo, Fang.
What?
Apa?
You heard what Hagrid said. "Follow the spiders.”
Kau dengar kata Hagrid. “Ikuti laba-laba."
They're heading to the Dark Forest.
Mereka menuju ke Hutan Terlarang.
Why spiders? Why couldn't it be “follow the butterflies”?
Kenapa harus laba-laba? Kenapa tidak “Ikuti kupu-kupu"?
Harry, I don’t like this.
Harry, aku tak suka ini.
-Harry, I don’t like this at all. -Shush!
Harry, aku benar-benar tak suka ini.
Can we go back now?
Kita bisa kembali sekarang?
Come on.
Ayo.
Who is it?
Siapa itu?
Don't panic.
Jangan panik.
Hagrid?
Hagrid?
Is that you?
Kaukah itu?
We're friends of Hagrid’s.
Kami teman-teman Hagrid.
And you? You're Aragog, aren't you?
Dan kau? Kau Aragog, bukan?
Yes.
Ya.
Hagrid has never sent men into our hollow before.
Hagrid tak pernah mengirim orang lain ke gua kami.
He’s in trouble. Up at the school, there have been attacks.
la dalam bahaya. Di sekolah terjadi serangan-serangan.
They think it’s Hagrid.
Mereka pikir pelakunya Hagrid.
They think he opened the Chamber of Secrets. Like before.
Mereka pikir ia membuka Kamar Rahasia. Seperti sebelumnya.
That's a lie.
Itu bohong.
Hagrid never opened the Chamber of Secrets.
Hagrid tak pernah membuka Kamar Rahasia.
-Then you're not the monster? -No.
Jadi kau bukan monsternya?! Bukan.
The monster was born in the castle.
Monster itu lahir di kastil itu.
l came to Hagrid from a distant land in the pocket of a traveler.
Aku datang ke Hagrid dari negeri jauh, di kantong pengelana.
Harry.
Harry.
But if you're not the monster, then what did kill that girl 50 years ago?
Tapi jika bukan kau, lalu siapa pembunuh gadis itu 50 tahun lalu?
We do not speak of it.
Kami tak bisa membicarakannya.
It is an ancient creature we spiders fear above all others.
la adalah mahluk kuno yang paling kami takuti.
But have you seen it?
Tapi apakah kau pernah melihatnya?
Il never saw any part of the castle but the box in which Hagrid kept me.
Aku tak pernah lihat kastil selain di kotak tempat Hagrid menyimpanku.
The girl was discovered in a bathroom.
Gadis itu ditemukan di dalam kamar mandi.
When I was accused, Hagrid brought me here.
Waktu aku dituduh membunuhnya, Hagrid membawaku ke sini.
-Harry! -What?
Harry!! Apa?
Well, thank you.
Terima kasih.
We'll just go.
Kami pergi dulu.
Go?
Pergi?
I think not.
Tidak bisa.
My sons and daughters do not harm Hagrid on my command.
Anak-anakku tak menyerang Hagrid atas perintahku.
But I cannot deny them fresh meat...
Tapi aku tak bisa membiarkan daging segar...
...when it wanders so willingly into our midst.
...yang dengan rela memasuki sarang kami.
Goodbye, friend of Hagrid.
Selamat tinggal, teman Hagrid.
Can we panic now?
Kita sudah boleh panik?
Know any spells?
Kau tahu mantra yang cocok?
One, but it’s not powerful enough for all of them.
Satu, tapi tak cukup kuat untuk mengusir mereka semua.
Where's Hermione when you need her?
Di mana Hermione jika kita sedang butuh dia?
Let’s go!
Ayo!
Arania Exumai!
Arania Exumai!
Glad we’re out of there.
Syukurlah kita sudah pergi dari sana.
Arania Exumai!
Arania Exumai!
-Thanks for that. -Don't mention it.
Terima kasih! Kembali.
Get us out of here.
Bawa kami pergi dari sini.
Now!
Sekarang!
Come on! Come on, move faster!
Ayo! Ayo, lebih cepat lagi!
Come on! Go!
Ayo! Cepat!
Get us in the air.
Terbangkan kita.
The flying gear’s jammed!
Gigi terbangnya macet!
-Come on! Pull! -I'm trying!
Ayo! Naik!! Aku sedang mencobanya!
Follow the spiders.
Ikuti laba-laba.
If Hagrid ever gets out of Azkaban, PIL kill him.
Jika Hagrid keluar dari Azkaban, kubunuh dia.
I mean, what was the point of sending us in there?
Maksudku, untuk apa ia menyuruh kita ke sana?
-What have we found out? -We know one thing.
Apa yang kita dapatkan?! Kita tahu satu hal.
Hagrid never opened the Chamber of Secrets.
Hagrid tak pernah membuka Kamar Rahasia.
He was innocent.
la tak bersalah.
Wish you were here, Hermione.
Andai kau di sini, Hermione.
We need you.
Kami membutuhkanmu.
Now more than ever.
Lebih dari sebelumnya.
-What’s that? -Ron....
Apa itu?! Ron...
This is why Hermione was in the library the day she was attacked.
Inilah alasan Hermione pergi ke perpustakaan di hari ia diserang.
Come on.
Ayo.
"Of the many fearsome beasts that roam our land...
“Dari banyak mahluk yang ditakuti dan berkeliaran di negeri kita...
..-none is more deadly than the basilisk. Capable of living for hundreds of years...
...yang terhebat adalah Basilisk. la bisa hidup ratusan tahun...
...instant death awaits any who meet this giant serpent’s eye.
..dan kematian menunggu siapapun yang menatap mata ular besar ini.
Spiders flee before it.” Ron, this is it.
Laba-laba takut melihatnya." Ron, itu dia.
The monster in the Chamber of Secrets is a basilisk.
Monster di Kamar Rahasia adalah Basilisk.
That's why I can hear it speak. It’s a snake.
Karena itulah aku bisa mendengarnya bicara. Monster itu seekor ular.
But if it kills by looking people in the eye, why is it no one’s dead?
Tapi jika tewas memandangnya, kenapa tak ada yang tewas?
Because no one did look it in the eye.
Karena tak ada yang menatap matanya.
Not directly, at least.
Setidaknya tak langsung.
Colin saw it through his camera.
Colin melihatnya lewat kameranya.
Justin-- Justin must have seen the basilisk through Nearly Headless Nick.
Justin pasti melihatnya melalui Nick Si Kepala-Nyaris-Putus.
Nick got the full blast of it. But he’s a ghost, he couldn't die again.
Nick yang lihat. Tapi ia hantu, ia tak bisa mati lagi.
And Hermione had the mirror.
Dan Hermione membawa cermin.
I bet you she was using it to look around corners in case it came along.
la pasti membawanya untuk berjaga-jaga jika Basilisk datang.
And Mrs. Norris?
Dan Ny. Norris?
I'm pretty sure she didn’t have a camera or a mirror, Harry.
la pasti tak punya kamera atau cermin, Harry.
The water.
Air itu.
There was water on the floor that night. She only saw the basilisk’s reflection.
Malam itu ada genangan air. la hanya lihat bayangan Basilisk.
"Spiders flee before it.”
“Laba-laba takut melihatnya."
-It all fits. -But how’s a basilisk been getting around?
Semuanya cocok!Tapi bagaimana Basilisk bisa berkeliaran?
A dirty, great snake. Someone would have seen it.
Ular besar dan jahat pasti mudah terlihat.
-Hermione’s answered that too. -Pipes? It’s using the plumbing.
Hermione juga sudah menjawabnya! Pipa? la memakai saluran air.
Remember what Aragog said about that girl 50 years ago?
Ingat waktu Aragog cerita tentang gadis itu 50 tahun yang lalu?
She died in a bathroom? What if she never left?
Ia tewas di kamar mandi? Bagaimana jika ia tak pernah pergi?
Moaning Myrtle.
Myrtle Merana.
All students are to return to their house dormitories at once.
Semua siswa harus segera kembali ke asramanya.
All teachers to the second-floor corridor immediately.
Seluruh guru diminta segera ke koridor lantai dua.
As you can see, the Heir of Slytherin has left another message.
Seperti kalian lihat, Pewaris Slytherin meninggalkan pesan lagi.
Our worst fear has been realized.
Kengerian terbesar kita sudah terwujud.
A student has been taken by the monster into the Chamber itself.
Seorang siswa dibawa monster itu ke Kamar Rahasia.
The students must be sent home. I'm afraid this is the end of Hogwarts.
Para siswa harus dipulangkan. Kurasa ini akhir sekolah Hogwarts.
So sorry. Dozed off. What have I missed?
Maaf. Aku ketiduran. Ada apa?
A girl has been snatched by the monster, Lockhart. Your moment has come at last.
Seorang gadis diculik monster itu. Akhirnya kesempatanmu datang juga.
-My moment? -Weren’t you saying just last night...
Kesempatanku?! Bukankah kau semalam bilang...
...that you’ve known all along where the entrance to the Chamber of Secrets is?
...kau sudah tahu di mana Kamar Rahasia itu berada?
That's settled. We'll leave you to deal with the monster, Gilderoy.
Itu dia. Kami akan meninggalkanmu untuk membereskan monster itu.
-Your skills, after all, are legend. -Very well.
Lagipula keahlianmu sudah melegenda! Baiklah.
I'll just be in my office getting....
Aku akan ke kantorku untuk...
Getting ready.
..bersiap-siap.
Who is it that the monster's taken, Minerva?
Siapa yang diculik monster itu, Minerva?
Ginny Weasley.
Ginny Weasley.
“Her skeleton will lie in the Chamber forever.”
“Kerangkanya akan terbaring selamanya di Kamar Rahasia."
Ginny.
Ginny.
Lockhart may be useless, but he’s going to try and get into the Chamber.
Lockhart mungkin tak berguna, tapi ia akan coba ke Kamar Rahasia.
At least we can tell him what we know.
Setidaknya kita bisa mengatakan apa yang kita ketahui padanya.
Professor, we have some information for you.
Profesor, kami punya informasi untuk Anda.
Are you going somewhere?
Profesor ingin pergi?
Well, yes. Urgent call. Unavoidable. Got to go.
Ya. Panggilan mendesak. Tak bisa dihindari. Aku harus pergi.
-What about my sister? -Well....
Bagaimana dengan adikku?! Yah...
As to that, most unfortunate. No one regrets more than I.
Untuk itu, sayang sekali. Aku yang paling menyesal.
You're the Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher. You can’t go now.
Anda guru Pertahanan Melawan Ilmu Hitam. Anda tak bisa pergi sekarang.
I must say, when I took the job, there was nothing in the description--
Waktu kuterima pekerjaan ini, tak ada yang menjabarkan...
You're running away?
Anda akan kabur?
-After all you did in your books? -Books can be misleading.
Setelah semua tulisanmu di buku?! Buku bisa menyesatkan.
-You wrote them. -My dear boy, do use your common sense.
Anda sendiri yang menulisnya! Pakai akal sehatmu, anak muda.
My books wouldn't have sold half as well if people didn’t think I'd done those things.
Bukuku tak mungkin laris kalau mereka pikir bukan aku tokohnya.
You're a fraud.
Kau penipu.
You've been taking credit for what other wizards have done.
Kau menerima pujian untuk perbuatan penyihir lain.
Is there anything you can do?
Adakah yang bisa Anda lakukan?
Yes, now you mention it. I'm rather gifted with Memory Charms.
Ya, karena kau menyebutkannya. Aku punya Jimat Memori.
Otherwise, all those wizards would have gone blabbing.
Kalau tidak, semua penyihir itu pasti sudah mengoceh.
I'd never have sold another book.
Aku tak bisa menjual buku-bukuku lagi.
In fact, I’m going to have to do the same to you.
Malah aku terpaksa melakukan hal yang sama dengan kalian.
Don't even think about it.
Jangan coba-coba.
Who's there?
Siapa itu?
Hello, Harry.
Halo, Harry.
-What do you want? -To ask you how you died.
Apa maumu?! Bertanya bagaimana kau meninggal.
It was dreadful.
Mengerikan sekali.
It happened right here in this very cubicle.
Terjadinya di sini, di bilik yang ini.
I'd hidden because Olive Hornby was teasing me about my glasses.
Aku sembunyi karena Olive Hornby mengejek kaca mataku.
I was crying, and then l heard somebody come in.
Aku sedang menangis waktu kudengar seseorang masuk.
-Who was it, Myrtle? -I don’t know. I was distraught!
Siapa orangnya, Myrtle?! Aku tak tahu. Aku sedang bingung.
But they said something funny, a kind of made-up language.
Tapi mereka berbicara lucu, semacam bahasa aneh.
And I realized it was a boy, so I unlocked the door to tell him to go away and...
Aku sadar itu suara laki-laki, jadi kubuka pintu, mengusirnya...
-...1 died. -Just like that? How?
...dan aku mati! Begitu saja? Bagaimana caranya?
I just remember seeing a pair of great, big, yellow eyes...
Aku hanya ingat melihat sepasang mata besar dan kuning...
...over there by that sink.
...Gi balik keran itu.
This is it.
Ini dia.
This is it, Ron. I think this is the entrance to the Chamber of Secrets.
Ini dia, Ron. Kurasa inilah pintu masuk ke Kamar Rahasia.
Say something. Harry, say something in Parseltongue.
Katakan sesuatu sesuatu dalam bahasa Parseltongue, Harry.
Excellent, Harry. Good work. Well, then, I'll just be....
Bagus, Harry. Kalau begitu aku akan...
There’s no need for me to stay.
Tak ada gunanya aku di sini.
Yes, there is.
Anda harus di sini.
-You first. -Now, boys, what good will it do?
Anda duluan! Apa gunanya, anak-anak?
Better you than us.
Lebih baik Anda daripada kami.
But-- Obviously, yes.
Tapi... Baiklah.
Sure you don't want to test it first?
Anda tak mau memeriksanya dulu?
It’s really quite filthy down here.
Di dalam menyeramkan sekali.
-All right. Let’s go. -Oh, Harry?
Baiklah. Ayo! Harry?
If you die down there, you're welcome to share my toilet.
Kalau kau tewas di sini, kau boleh berbagi toilet denganku.
Thanks, Myrtle.
Terima kasih, Myrtle.
Now, remember: Any sign of movement, close your eyes straightaway.
Sekarang, ingat. Jika ada gerakan, pejamkan mata kalian segera.
Go on.
Ayo.
This way.
Lewat sini.
-What's this? -It looks like a snake.
Apa ini?! Seperti ular.
-It's a snakeskin. -Bloody hell.
Itu kulit ularf Astaga.
Whatever shed this must be 60 feet long. Or more.
Apapun mahluk itu pasti panjangnya 60 kaki. Atau lebih.
Heart of a lion, this one.
Dasar pemberani.
The adventure ends here, boys. But don’t fret.
Petualangan berakhir di sini, anak-anak. Tapi jangan takut.
The world will know our story. How I was too late to save the girl.
Dunia akan tahu. Bagaimana aku terlambat menyelamatkan gadis itu.
How you two tragically lost your minds...
Bagaimana kalian berdua gila dengan tragis...
..at the sight of her mangled body.
..begitu melihat mayat gadis itu.
So....
Jadi...
You first, Mr. Potter.
Kau duluan, Tn. Potter.
Say goodbye to your memories.
Ucapkan selamat tinggal kepada ingatanmu.
Obliviate!
Obliviate!
-Ron! Ron, are you okay? -I'm fine.
Ron! Kau baik-baik saja?! Aku tak apa-apa.
Hello.
Halo.
Who are you?
Siapa kau?
-Ron Weasley. -Really?
Ron Weasley! Sungguh?
And who am I?
Dan aku siapa?
Lockhart’s Memory Charm backfired. He hasn't got a clue who he is.
Jimat Memori Lockhart makan tuan. latak ingat siapa dirinya.
It’s an odd sort of place, isn't it?
Tempat ini aneh, ya?
Do you live here?
Kau tinggal di sini?
-No. -Really?
Tidak Sungguh?
-What do I do now? -You wait here...
Apa yang harus kulakukan?! Tunggu di sini...
...and try and shift some of this rock so we can get back through.
..dan coba bongkar tumpukan batu-batunya agar kami bisa lewat.
-l'll go on and find Ginny. -Okay.
Aku akan mencari Ginny! Baiklah.
Ginny! Ginny, please don’t be dead. Wake up, wake up.
Ginny, tolong jangan mati. Bangun!
Please wake up.
Kumohon, bangunlah.
She won't wake.
latak akan bangun.
Tom. Tom Riddle. What do you mean, she won't wake?
Tom. Tom Riddle. Apa maksudmu ia takkan bangun?
-She’s not...? -She's still alive, but only just.
la tidak...?! la masih hidup. Tapi seperti itu.
-Are you a ghost? -A memory...
Kau hantu?! Kenangan...
...preserved in a diary for 50 years.
...yang tersimpan dalam buku harian selama 50 tahun.
She's cold as ice. Ginny, please don’t be dead. Wake up.
la sedingin es. Ginny, tolong jangan mati. Bangun.
You've got to help me, Tom. There’s a basilisk.
Kau harus membantuku, Tom. Di sana ada ular Basilisk.
It won't come until it’s called.
la takkan datang sampai dipanggil.
-Give me my wand, Tom. -You won't be needing it.
Berikan tongkatku, Tom! Kau tak memerlukannya.
-We've got to go. We've got to save her. -I'm afraid I can’t do that.
Kita harus pergi selamatkan Ginny! Sayang sekali aku tak bisa.
You see, as poor Ginny grows weaker, I grow stronger.
Sementara Ginny makin lemah, aku makin kuat.
Yes, Harry, it was Ginny Weasley who opened the Chamber of Secrets.
Ya, Harry. Ginny Weasley-lah yang membuka Kamar Rahasia itu.
No. She couldn't. She wouldn't.
Tidak. la tak bisa melakukannya. la tak mungkin melakukannya.
It was Ginny who set the basilisk on the Mudbloods and Filch’s cat...
Ginny yang melepaskan Basilisk ke para Darah-lumpur dan kucing Filch.
...Ginny who wrote the threatening messages on the walls.
Ginny yang menulis pesan ancaman di dinding.
-But why? -Because I told her to.
Kenapa?! Karena aku yang menyuruhnya.
You'll find ! can be very persuasive. Not that she knew what she was doing.
Aku bisa sangat memikat. Tapi ia tak sadari perbuatannya.
She was, shall we say, in a kind of trance.
la mengalami apa yang kita sebut, kerasukan.
Still, the power of the diary began to scare her.
Tapi, kekuatan buku harian itu mulai menakutkan baginya.
She tried to dispose of it in the girls’ bathroom.
la berusaha membenamkannya di toilet wanita.
And then who should find it but you?
Dan siapa yang menemukannya kalau bukan kau?
The very person l was most anxious to meet.
Orang yang ingin sekali kutemui.
And why did you want to meet me?
Kenapa kau ingin bertemu denganku?
I knew I had to talk to you, meet you if I could.
Aku tahu aku harus bicara atau bertemu denganmu jika perlu.
So I decided to show you my capture of that brainless oaf Hagrid...
Jadi kuputuskan menunjukkan saat kutangkap basah si bodoh Hagrid...
-...to gain your trust. -Hagrid’s my friend.
..untuk membangkitkan percayamu! Hagrid temanku.
-And you framed him, didn't you? -It was my word against Hagrid’s.
Dan kau menjebaknya, bukan?! Tuduhanku melawan pembelaannya.
Only Dumbledore seemed to think he was innocent.
Hanya Dumbledore yang menganggapnya tak bersalah.
'll bet Dumbledore saw tight through you.
Pasti Dumbledore juga bisa menebak sifatmu.
He certainly kept an annoyingly close watch on me after that.
Setelah itu ia mengawasiku dengan ketat.
I knew it wouldn't be safe to open the Chamber again while I was still at school...
Aku tahu tak aman membuka lagi Kamar itu selama masih di sekolah.
...80 I decided to leave behind a diary...
Jadi kuputuskan untuk meninggalkan buku harian.
...preserving my 16-year-old self in its pages...
Dan menyimpan diriku saat berumur 16 tahun di dalam halamannya.
...So that one day I would be able to lead another...
Agar suatu hari aku bisa membimbing yang lain...
...to finish Salazar Slytherin’s noble work.
..untuk menyelesaikan tugas mulia Salazar Slytherin.
Well, you haven't finished it this time.
Kali ini kau tak sempat menyelesaikannya.
In a few hours, the Mandrake Draught will be ready.
Dalam beberapa jam, Ramuan Mandrake akan siap.
And everyone who was Petrified will be all right again.
Dan semua yang dibatukan akan kembali pulih.
Haven't I told you? Killing Mudbloods doesn’t matter to me anymore.
Aku belum bilang? Membunuh Darah-lumpur tak berarti lagi.
For many months now, my new target has been you.
Beberapa bulan ini, sasaran baruku adalah kau.
How is it that a baby with no extraordinary magical talent...
Bagaimana seorang bayi tanpa bakat sihir yang hebat...
...was able to defeat the greatest wizard of all time?
..bisa mengalahkan penyihir terhebat sepanjang masa?
How did you escape with nothing but a scar...
Bagaimana kau bisa selamat dan hanya meninggalkan bekas luka.
...while Lord Voldemort’s powers were destroyed?
Sementara kekuatan Lord Voldermort musnah.
Why do you care how I escaped? Voldemort was after your time.
Kenapa kau peduli caraku selamat? Voldemort ada setelah masamu.
Voldemort is my past, present and future.
Voldemort adalah masa lalu, masa kini dan masa depanku.
You. You're the Heir of Slytherin.
Kau. Kau Pewaris Slytherin.
-You're Voldemort. -Surely you didn’t think...
Kau Voldemort! Kau pasti tak menyangka...
... 1 was going to keep my filthy Muggle father’s name?
...aku akan memakai nama Muggle ayahku, bukan?
No. I fashioned myself a new name, a name I knew wizards everywhere...
Tidak. Aku menemukan nama baruku, yang aku tahu penyihir mana pun...
..-would one day fear to speak when I became the greatest sorcerer in the world.
..akan ketakutan menyebutnya saat aku jadi penyihir terhebat.
Albus Dumbledore is the greatest sorcerer in the world.
Albus Dumbledore adalah penyihir terhebat di dunia.
Dumbledore’s been driven out of this castle by the mere memory of me.
Dumbledore disingkirkan dari kastil ini karena kenanganku.
He’ll never be gone. Not as long as those who remain are loyal to him.
latakkan pergi. Selama yang tinggal di sini setia padanya.
Fawkes?
Fawkes?
So this is what Dumbledore sends his great defender.
Jadi Dumbledore mengirim pelindung terbaiknya.
A songbird and an old hat.
Seekor burung dan topi tua.
Let's match the power of Lord Voldemort, Heir of Salazar Slytherin...
Kita adu kekuatan Lord Voldemort, Keturunan Salazar Slytherin...
.. against the famous Harry Potter.
..melawan Harry Potter yang terkenal.
Parseltongue won't save you now, Potter. It only obeys me.
Parseltongue takkan menyelamatkanmu. la hanya patuh padaku.
No!
Tidak!
Your bird may have blinded the basilisk, but it can still hear you.
Burungmu bisa membutakan ular itu, tapi ia masih bisa mendengarmu.
Yes, Potter. The process is nearly complete.
Ya, Potter. Prosesnya hampir selesai.
In a few minutes, Ginny Weasley will be dead, and I will cease to be a memory.
Sebentar lagi Ginny Weasley mati. Dan aku tak lagi sekedar kenangan.
Lord Voldemort will return...
Lord Voldemort akan kembali...
..-very much alive.
..dan hidup!
Ginny?
Ginny?
Remarkable, isn’t it...
Hebat bukan?
..-how quickly the venom of the basilisk penetrates the body?
Betapa cepatnya racun ular itu menjalari tubuhmu.
I'd guess you have little more than a minute to live.
Waktumu bertahan hidup tak lebih dari semenit.
You'll be with your dear Mudblood mother soon, Harry.
Kau akan segera bertemu ibumu yang berdarah-lumpur itu, Harry.
Funny, the damage a silly little book can do...
Aneh, betapa besar bencana yang diakibatkan buku kecil konyol itu.
..-especially in the hands of a silly little girl.
Apa lagi di tangan seorang gadis kecil yang konyol.
What are you doing?
Apa yang kaulakukan?
Stop. No!
Berhenti. Tidak!
It was me. But I swear, I didn’t mean to.
Aku yang melakukannya. Tapi aku tak bermaksud melakukannya.
Riddle made me, and....
Ridle yang menyuruhku dan...
Harry, you're hurt.
Harry, kau terluka.
Don't worry.
Jangan takut.
Ginny, you need to get yourself out.
Ginny, kau harus keluar dari sini.
Follow the Chamber and you'll find Ron.
Ikuti lorong Kamar ini dan kau akan menemukan Ron.
You were brilliant, Fawkes.
Kau hebat sekali, Fawkes.
I just wasn't quick enough.
Tapi aku kurang gesit.
Of course.
Tentu saja.
Phoenix tears have healing powers.
Air mata Phoenix punya kekuatan menyembuhkan.
Thanks.
Terima kasih.
It’s all right, Ginny.
Tenanglah, Ginny.
It’s over.
Semua sudah selesai.
It’s just a memory.
Ini hanya kenangan.
Amazing! This is just like magic!
Hebat! Ini seperti sihir!
You both realize, of course...
Kalian berdua tentu menyadari...
...that in the past few hours, you have broken perhaps a dozen school rules.
..bahwa kalian mungkin melanggar selusin peraturan sekolah.
Yes, sir.
Ya, Pak.
There is sufficient evidence to have you both expelled.
Ada cukup bukti untuk mengeluarkan kalian berdua.
Yes, sir.
Ya, Pak.
Therefore, it is only fitting...
Untuk itu, kalian berdua hanya pantas...
...that you both receive...
...untuk menerima...
... Special Awards for Services to the School.
..penghargaan istimewa atas pengabdian kalian pada sekolah.
Thanks, sir.
Terima kasih, Pak.
Now, Mr. Weasley, if you would...
Sekarang, Tn. Weasley, utuslah burung hantumu...
...have an owl deliver these release papers to Azkaban.
..mengantar surat pembebasan ini ke Azkaban.
I believe we want our gamekeeper back.
Kita pasti menginginkan pengawas hewan kita kembali.
First, 1 want to thank you, Harry.
Pertama-tama, aku ingin berterima kasih padamu, Harry.
You must have shown me real loyalty down in the Chamber.
Kau pasti menunjukkan kesetiaan sejati di Kamar Rahasia.
Nothing but that could have called Fawkes to you.
Hanya itu yang membuat Fawkes datang padamu.
And...
Dan...
..- second...
...kedua...
... [sense that something is troubling you.
..aku merasa ada yang mengganggu pikiranmu sekarang.
Am I right, Harry?
Aku benar, Harry?
It’s just....
Aku hanya...
You see, sir, 1 couldn't help but notice certain things, certain....
Aku terus memikirkan beberapa hal.
Certain similarities between Tom Riddle and me.
Beberapa kesamaan antara Tom Riddle dan aku.
I see.
Aku paham.
Well, you can speak Parseltongue, Harry. Why?
Kau bisa bicara Parseltongue. Kenapa?
Because Lord Voldemort can speak Parseltongue.
Karena Lord Voldemort bisa berbahasa Parseltongue.
If I'm not mistaken, Harry...
Kalau aku tak salah...
...he transferred some of his powers to you...
..ia menurunkan beberapa keahliannya padamu...
...the night he gave you that scar.
...Saat ia memberimu bekas luka itu.
Voldemort transferred some of his powers to me?
Voldemort menurunkan beberapa kekuatannya padaku?
Not intentionally...
Meski sebenarnya secara tak disengaja.
...but yes.
Tapi, ya.
So the Sorting Hat was right. l should be in Slytherin.
Jadi Topi Seleksi benar. Aku mestinya tinggal di Slytherin.
It’s true. You possess many of the qualities that Voldemort himself prizes.
Benar. Kau memiliki beberapa keahlian kebanggaan Voldemort.
Determination, resourcefulness...
Ketetapan hatimu, kecerdikanmu...
...and if l may say so, a certain disregard for the rules.
..dan kalau boleh kubilang, sikap tak acuh pada peraturan.
Why, then, did the Sorting Hat place you in Gryffindor?
Lalu kenapa Topi Seleksi memasukkanmu ke Gryffindor?
-Because I asked it to. -Exactly, Harry. Exactly.
Karena aku memintanya! Tepat sekali, Harry.
Which makes you different from Voldemort.
Dan itu menjadikanmu lain dari Voldemort.
It is not our abilities that show what we truly are.
Bukan kemampuan kita yang bisa menunjukkan siapa diri kita.
It is our choices.
Tapi pilihan kita.
If you want proof why you belong in Gryffindor...
Jika kau ingin bukti kenapa kau pantas masuk ke Gryffindor...
...then I suggest you look more closely at this.
...maka kusarankan kaulihat ini baik-baik.
Be careful.
Hati-hati.
Godric Gryffindor.
Godric Gryffindor.
It would take a true Gryffindor to pull that out of the hat.
Hanya Gryffindor sejati yang bisa mengeluarkan pedang dari topinya.
Dobby.
Dobby.
So this is your master. The family you serve is the Malfoys.
Jadi dia majikanmu. Keluarga yang menjadi tuanmu adalah Malfoy.
lll deal with you later.
Nanti aku bicara padamu.
Out of my way, Potter.
Minggir, Potter.
So it’s true. You have returned.
Jadi benar. Kau sudah kembali.
When the governors learned that Arthur Weasley’s daughter...
Waktu Dewan Sekolah tahu puteri Arthur Weasley...
...-was taken into the Chamber, they saw fit to summon me back.
..diculik ke Kamar Rahasia itu, mereka menugaskanku lagi.
-Ridiculous. -Curiously, Lucius, several of them...
Tak masuk akal! Anehnya, Lucius...
..-were under the impression that you would curse their family...
..beberapa dari mereka merasa kau akan mengutuk keluarganya...
..jif they did not agree to suspend me in the first place.
..jika mereka tak setuju untuk menskorsku.
-How dare you! -Beg your pardon?
Berani sekali kau!! Maaf?
My sole concern has always been and will always be...
Perhatian utamaku sejak dulu dan selalu...
...the welfare of this school...
..adalah kesejahteraan sekolah ini.
...and, of course, its students.
Dan tentu saja, siswa-siswanya.
The culprit has been identified, l presume?
Kurasa pelaku kejahatannya sudah ketahuan, bukan?
Yes.
Ya.
And?
Lalu?
Who was it?
Siapa pelakunya?
Voldemort.
Voldemort.
Only this time he chose to act through somebody else...
Tapi kali ini ia memilih untuk beraksi melalui orang lain...
...by means of this.
...lewat buku ini.
I see.
Begitu.
Fortunately, our young Mr. Potter discovered it.
Beruntung sekali, Tn. Potter berhasil mengetahuinya.
One hopes that no more of Lord Voldemort’s old school-things...
Ada yang berharap perbuatan lama Lord Voldemort di sekolah...
...should find their way into innocent hands.
...bisa kembali lewat orang yang bersih.
The consequences for the one responsible would be...
Hukuman bagi orang yang bertanggung jawab...
... Severe.
...akan berat sekali.
Well, let us hope...
Kita berharap saja...
...that Mr. Potter will always be around to save the day.
...Tn. Potter akan selalu ada di sini untuk menyelamatkannya.
Don't worry. I will be.
Jangan khawatir. Aku akan melakukannya.
Dumbledore.
Dumbledore.
Come, Dobby. We're leaving.
Ayo, Dobby. Kita pulang.
Sir? I wonder if I could have that?
Pak, aku boleh minta buku itu?
Mr. Malfoy.
Tn. Malfoy.
Mr. Malfoy!
Tn. Malfoy!
l have something of yours.
Aku membawa sesuatu milik Anda.
Mine? I don’t know what you're talking about.
Milikku? Aku tak tahu apa maksudmu.
You do, do you?
Begitu?
Come, Dobby.
Ayo, Dobby.
Open it.
Buka buku itu.
Master has given Dobby a sock.
Tuan memberi Dobby kaos kaki.
What? I didn’t give--
Apa? Aku tak memberimu...
Master has presented Dobby with clothes.
Tuan memberikan baju pada Dobby.
You lost me my servant!
Kau membuatku kehilangan pelayan!
Your parents were meddlesome fools too.
Orang tuamu juga suka ikut campur.
Harry Potter freed Dobby. How can Dobby ever repay him?
Harry Potter membebaskan Dobby. Bagaimana cara Dobby membalas budi?
-Just promise me something. -Anything, sir.
Berjanjilah satu hal padaku! Apapun, Tuan.
-Welcome back, Sir Nicholas. -Thank you.
Selamat datang, Sir Nicholas! Terima kasih.
-Good evening, Sir Nicholas. -Good evening.
Selamat malam, Sir Nicholas! Selamat malam.
-Good to see you, Sir Nicholas. -Thank you.
Senang bertemu lagi, Sir Nicholas! Terima kasih.
Harry. It’s Hermione.
Harry. Itu Hermione.
Congratulations. I can’t believe you solved it.
Selamat. Aku tak percaya kalian berhasil memecahkannya.
We had loads of help from you.
Kami dapat banyak bantuan darimu.
-We couldn't have done it without you. -Thanks.
Kami tak mungkin berhasil tanpamu! Terima kasih.
Before we begin the feast...
Sebelum kita mulai makan...
...whose Mandrake juice has been so successfully administered...
...yang mana jus Mandrake-nya telah dengan sukses...
...to all who had been Petrified.
..menyembuhkan semua yang telah membatu.
Also, in light of the recent events...
Dan mengenai beberapa kejadian belakangan ini,...
...as a school treat...
..sebagai hadiah dari sekolah...
Sorry I'm late.
Maaf aku terlambat.
The owl that delivered my release papers got all lost and confused.
Burung hantu yang mengantar surat pembebasanku tersesat.
Some ruddy bird called Errol.
Burung itu bernama Errol.
...[ would still be you-know-where...
Aku akan masih berada di kalian-tahu-di mana.
...so I'd just like to say thanks.
Jadi aku hanya ingin berterima kasih.
[ENGLISH]
R3-Indonesian